<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="sun.rmi.rmic">
        <import package="sun.tools.java.Identifier"/>
        <class name="Names" line="30">
            <javadoc line="30">
                Names provides static utility methods used by other rmic classes
                  for dealing with identifiers.
                  WARNING: The contents of this source file are not part of any
                  supported API.  Code that depends on them does so at its own risk:
                  they are subject to change or removal without notice.                
            </javadoc>
            <javadoc line="40">
                Return stub class name for impl class name.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="stubFor" type="Identifier" line="43">
                <params>
                    <param name="name" type="Identifier"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="47">
                Return skeleton class name for impl class name.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="skeletonFor" type="Identifier" line="50">
                <params>
                    <param name="name" type="Identifier"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="54">
                If necessary, convert a class name to its mangled form, i.e. the
                  non-inner class name used in the binary representation of
                  inner classes.  This is necessary to be able to name inner
                  classes in the generated source code in places where the language
                  does not permit it, such as when synthetically defining an inner
                  class outside of its outer class, and for generating file names
                  corresponding to inner classes.
                  Currently this mangling involves modifying the internal names of
                  inner classes by converting occurrences of &quot;. &quot; into &quot;$&quot;.
                  This code is taken from the &quot;mangleInnerType&quot; method of
                  the &quot;sun.tools.java.Type&quot; class; this method cannot be accessed
                  itself because it is package protected.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="mangleClass" type="Identifier" line="70">
                <params>
                    <param name="className" type="Identifier"/>
                </params>
                <comment line="74">
                    Get &apos;.&apos; qualified inner class name (with outer class
                     qualification and no package qualification) and replace
                     each &apos;.&apos; with &apos;$&apos;.                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="85">
                    prepend package qualifier back for returned identifier                    
                </comment>
                <declaration name="mangled" type="Identifier" line="79"/>
            </method>
        </class>
    </source>