<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="javax.swing.event">
        <import package="javax.swing.undo"/>
        <import package="javax.swing.text"/>
        <interface name="DocumentEvent">
            <javadoc line="4">
                Interface for document change notifications.  This provides
                  detailed information to Document observers about how the
                  Document changed.  It provides high level information such
                  as type of change and where it occurred, as well as the more
                  detailed structural changes (What Elements were inserted and
                  removed).                
                <author>
                    Timothy Prinzing                    
                </author>
                <see>
                    javax.swing.text.Document                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    DocumentListener                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getOffset" type="int" line="16"/>
            <javadoc line="16">
                Returns the offset within the document of the start
                  of the change.                
                <return>
                    the offset >= 0                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getLength" type="int" line="22"/>
            <javadoc line="22">
                Returns the length of the change.                
                <return>
                    the length >= 0                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getDocument" type="Document" line="27"/>
            <javadoc line="27">
                Gets the document that sourced the change event.                
                <return>
                    the document                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getType" type="EventType" line="32"/>
            <javadoc line="32">
                Gets the type of event.                
                <return>
                    the type                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getChange" type="ElementChange" line="37"/>
            <javadoc line="37">
                Gets the change information for the given element.
                  The change information describes what elements were
                  added and removed and the location.  If there were
                  no changes, null is returned.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  This method is for observers to discover the structural
                  changes that were made.  This means that only elements
                  that existed prior to the mutation (and still exist after
                  the mutatino) need to have ElementChange records.
                  The changes made available need not be recursive.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  For example, if the an element is removed from it&apos;s
                  parent, this method should report that the parent
                  changed and provide an ElementChange implementation
                  that describes the change to the parent.  If the
                  child element removed had children, these elements
                  do not need to be reported as removed.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  If an child element is insert into a parent element,
                  the parent element should report a change.  If the
                  child element also had elements inserted into it
                  (grandchildren to the parent) these elements need
                  not report change.                
                <param>
                    elem the element                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    the change information, or null if the
                      element was not modified                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <class name="EventType" line="66">
                <javadoc line="66">
                    Enumeration for document event types                    
                </javadoc>
                <method name="EventType" type="constructor" line="70">
                    <params>
                        <param name="s" type="String"/>
                    </params>
                </method>
                <declaration name="INSERT" type="EventType" line="73"/>
                <javadoc line="73">
                    Insert type.                    
                </javadoc>
                <declaration name="REMOVE" type="EventType" line="77"/>
                <javadoc line="77">
                    Remove type.                    
                </javadoc>
                <declaration name="CHANGE" type="EventType" line="81"/>
                <javadoc line="81">
                    Change type.                    
                </javadoc>
                <javadoc line="85">
                    Converts the type to a string.                    
                    <return>
                        the string                        
                    </return>
                </javadoc>
                <method name="toString" type="String" line="89"/>
                <declaration name="typeString" type="String" line="92"/>
            </class>
            <interface name="ElementChange">
                <javadoc line="94">
                    Describes changes made to a specific element.                    
                </javadoc>
                <method name="getElement" type="Element" line="98"/>
                <javadoc line="98">
                    Returns the element represented.  This is the element
                      that was changed.                    
                    <return>
                        the element                        
                    </return>
                </javadoc>
                <method name="getIndex" type="int" line="104"/>
                <javadoc line="104">
                    Fetches the index within the element represented.
                      This is the location that children were added
                      and/or removed.                    
                    <return>
                        the index >= 0                        
                    </return>
                </javadoc>
                <method name="getChildrenRemoved" type="Element[]" line="111"/>
                <javadoc line="111">
                    Gets the child elements that were removed from the
                      given parent element.  The element array returned is
                      sorted in the order that the elements used to lie in
                      the document, and must be contiguous.                    
                    <return>
                        the child elements                        
                    </return>
                </javadoc>
                <method name="getChildrenAdded" type="Element[]" line="119"/>
                <javadoc line="119">
                    Gets the child elements that were added to the given
                      parent element.  The element array returned is in the
                      order that the elements lie in the document, and must
                      be contiguous.                    
                    <return>
                        the child elements                        
                    </return>
                </javadoc>
            </interface>
        </interface>
    </source>