<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="java.lang">
        <import package="java.io.IOException"/>
        <interface name="Appendable">
            <javadoc line="3">
                An object to which &lt;tt&gt;char&lt;/tt&gt; sequences and values can be appended.  The
                  &lt;tt&gt;Appendable&lt;/tt&gt; interface must be implemented by any class whose
                  instances are intended to receive formatted output from a {@link java.util.Formatter}.
                  &lt;p&gt; The characters to be appended should be valid Unicode characters as
                  described in &lt;a href=&quot;Character.html#unicode&quot;&gt;Unicode Character
                  Representation&lt;/a&gt;.  Note that supplementary characters may be composed of
                  multiple 16-bit &lt;tt&gt;char&lt;/tt&gt; values.
                  &lt;p&gt; Appendables are not necessarily safe for multithreaded access.  Thread
                  safety is the responsibility of classes that extend and implement this
                  interface.
                  &lt;p&gt; Since this interface may be implemented by existing classes
                  with different styles of error handling there is no guarantee that
                  errors will be propagated to the invoker.                
                <since>
                    1.5                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="append" type="Appendable" line="20"/>
            <javadoc line="20">
                Appends the specified character sequence to this &lt;tt&gt;Appendable&lt;/tt&gt;.
                  &lt;p&gt; Depending on which class implements the character sequence
                  &lt;tt&gt;csq&lt;/tt&gt;, the entire sequence may not be appended.  For
                  instance, if &lt;tt&gt;csq&lt;/tt&gt; is a {@link java.nio.CharBuffer} then
                  the subsequence to append is defined by the buffer&apos;s position and limit.                
                <param>
                    csqThe character sequence to append.  If &lt;tt&gt;csq&lt;/tt&gt; is
                      &lt;tt&gt;null&lt;/tt&gt;, then the four characters &lt;tt&gt;&quot;null&quot;&lt;/tt&gt; are
                      appended to this Appendable.                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    A reference to this &lt;tt&gt;Appendable&lt;/tt&gt;                    
                </return>
                <throws>
                    IOExceptionIf an I/O error occurs                    
                </throws>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="append" type="Appendable" line="33"/>
            <javadoc line="33">
                Appends a subsequence of the specified character sequence to this
                  &lt;tt&gt;Appendable&lt;/tt&gt;.
                  &lt;p&gt; An invocation of this method of the form &lt;tt&gt;out.append(csq, start,
                  end)&lt;/tt&gt; when &lt;tt&gt;csq&lt;/tt&gt; is not &lt;tt&gt;null&lt;/tt&gt;, behaves in
                  exactly the same way as the invocation
                  &lt;pre&gt;
                  out.append(csq.subSequence(start, end)) &lt;/pre&gt;                
                <param>
                    csqThe character sequence from which a subsequence will be
                      appended.  If &lt;tt&gt;csq&lt;/tt&gt; is &lt;tt&gt;null&lt;/tt&gt;, then characters
                      will be appended as if &lt;tt&gt;csq&lt;/tt&gt; contained the four
                      characters &lt;tt&gt;&quot;null&quot;&lt;/tt&gt;.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    startThe index of the first character in the subsequence                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    endThe index of the character following the last character in the
                      subsequence                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    A reference to this &lt;tt&gt;Appendable&lt;/tt&gt;                    
                </return>
                <throws>
                    IndexOutOfBoundsExceptionIf &lt;tt&gt;start&lt;/tt&gt; or &lt;tt&gt;end&lt;/tt&gt; are negative, &lt;tt&gt;start&lt;/tt&gt;
                      is greater than &lt;tt&gt;end&lt;/tt&gt;, or &lt;tt&gt;end&lt;/tt&gt; is greater than
                      &lt;tt&gt;csq.length()&lt;/tt&gt;                    
                </throws>
                <throws>
                    IOExceptionIf an I/O error occurs                    
                </throws>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="append" type="Appendable" line="55"/>
            <javadoc line="55">
                Appends the specified character to this &lt;tt&gt;Appendable&lt;/tt&gt;.                
                <param>
                    cThe character to append                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    A reference to this &lt;tt&gt;Appendable&lt;/tt&gt;                    
                </return>
                <throws>
                    IOExceptionIf an I/O error occurs                    
                </throws>
            </javadoc>
        </interface>
    </source>