<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="java.awt.dnd">
        <class name="DragSourceAdapter" line="28">
            <implements interface="DragSourceListener"/>
            <implements interface="DragSourceMotionListener"/>
            <javadoc line="28">
                An abstract adapter class for receiving drag source events. The methods in
                  this class are empty. This class exists only as a convenience for creating
                  listener objects.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  Extend this class to create a &lt;code&gt;DragSourceEvent&lt;/code&gt; listener
                  and override the methods for the events of interest. (If you implement the
                  &lt;code&gt;DragSourceListener&lt;/code&gt; interface, you have to define all of
                  the methods in it. This abstract class defines null methods for them
                  all, so you only have to define methods for events you care about.)
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  Create a listener object using the extended class and then register it with
                  a &lt;code&gt;DragSource&lt;/code&gt;. When the drag enters, moves over, or exits
                  a drop site, when the drop action changes, and when the drag ends, the
                  relevant method in the listener object is invoked, and the
                  &lt;code&gt;DragSourceEvent&lt;/code&gt; is passed to it.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  The drop site is &lt;i&gt;associated with the previous &lt;code&gt;dragEnter()&lt;/code&gt;
                  invocation&lt;/i&gt; if the latest invocation of &lt;code&gt;dragEnter()&lt;/code&gt; on this
                  adapter corresponds to that drop site and is not followed by a
                  &lt;code&gt;dragExit()&lt;/code&gt; invocation on this adapter.                
                <see>
                    DragSourceEvent                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    DragSourceListener                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    DragSourceMotionListener                    
                </see>
                <author>
                    David Mendenhall                    
                </author>
                <since>
                    1.4                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <javadoc line="60">
                Called as the cursor&apos;s hotspot enters a platform-dependent drop site.
                  This method is invoked when all the following conditions are true:
                  &lt;UL&gt;
                  &lt;LI&gt;The cursor&apos;s hotspot enters the operable part of
                  a platform-dependent drop site.
                  &lt;LI&gt;The drop site is active.
                  &lt;LI&gt;The drop site accepts the drag.
                  &lt;/UL&gt;                
                <param>
                    dsde the <code>DragSourceDragEvent</code>                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="dragEnter" type="void" line="72">
                <params>
                    <param name="dsde" type="DragSourceDragEvent"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="74">
                Called as the cursor&apos;s hotspot moves over a platform-dependent drop site.
                  This method is invoked when all the following conditions are true:
                  &lt;UL&gt;
                  &lt;LI&gt;The cursor&apos;s hotspot has moved, but still intersects the
                  operable part of the drop site associated with the previous
                  dragEnter() invocation.
                  &lt;LI&gt;The drop site is still active.
                  &lt;LI&gt;The drop site accepts the drag.
                  &lt;/UL&gt;                
                <param>
                    dsde the <code>DragSourceDragEvent</code>                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="dragOver" type="void" line="87">
                <params>
                    <param name="dsde" type="DragSourceDragEvent"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="89">
                Called whenever the mouse is moved during a drag operation.                
                <param>
                    dsde the <code>DragSourceDragEvent</code>                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="dragMouseMoved" type="void" line="94">
                <params>
                    <param name="dsde" type="DragSourceDragEvent"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="96">
                Called when the user has modified the drop gesture.
                  This method is invoked when the state of the input
                  device(s) that the user is interacting with changes.
                  Such devices are typically the mouse buttons or keyboard
                  modifiers that the user is interacting with.                
                <param>
                    dsde the <code>DragSourceDragEvent</code>                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="dropActionChanged" type="void" line="105">
                <params>
                    <param name="dsde" type="DragSourceDragEvent"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="107">
                Called as the cursor&apos;s hotspot exits a platform-dependent drop site.
                  This method is invoked when any of the following conditions are true:
                  &lt;UL&gt;
                  &lt;LI&gt;The cursor&apos;s hotspot no longer intersects the operable part
                  of the drop site associated with the previous dragEnter() invocation.
                  &lt;/UL&gt;
                  OR
                  &lt;UL&gt;
                  &lt;LI&gt;The drop site associated with the previous dragEnter() invocation
                  is no longer active.
                  &lt;/UL&gt;
                  OR
                  &lt;UL&gt;
                  &lt;LI&gt; The drop site associated with the previous dragEnter() invocation
                  has rejected the drag.
                  &lt;/UL&gt;                
                <param>
                    dse the <code>DragSourceEvent</code>                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="dragExit" type="void" line="127">
                <params>
                    <param name="dse" type="DragSourceEvent"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="129">
                This method is invoked to signify that the Drag and Drop
                  operation is complete. The getDropSuccess() method of
                  the &lt;code&gt;DragSourceDropEvent&lt;/code&gt; can be used to
                  determine the termination state. The getDropAction() method
                  returns the operation that the drop site selected
                  to apply to the Drop operation. Once this method is complete, the
                  current &lt;code&gt;DragSourceContext&lt;/code&gt; and
                  associated resources become invalid.                
                <param>
                    dsde the <code>DragSourceDropEvent</code>                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="dragDropEnd" type="void" line="141">
                <params>
                    <param name="dsde" type="DragSourceDropEvent"/>
                </params>
            </method>
        </class>
    </source>