<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="java.awt">
        <interface name="LayoutManager2">
            <implements interface="LayoutManager"/>
            <javadoc line="2">
                Defines an interface for classes that know how to layout Containers
                  based on a layout constraints object.
                  This interface extends the LayoutManager interface to deal with layouts
                  explicitly in terms of constraint objects that specify how and where
                  components should be added to the layout.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  This minimal extension to LayoutManager is intended for tool
                  providers who wish to the creation of constraint-based layouts.
                  It does not yet provide full, general support for custom
                  constraint-based layout managers.                
                <see>
                    LayoutManager                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    Container                    
                </see>
                <author>
                    Jonni Kanerva                    
                </author>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="addLayoutComponent" type="void" line="18"/>
            <javadoc line="18">
                Adds the specified component to the layout, using the specified
                  constraint object.                
                <param>
                    comp the component to be added                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    constraints  where/how the component is added to the layout.                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="maximumLayoutSize" type="Dimension" line="25"/>
            <javadoc line="25">
                Calculates the maximum size dimensions for the specified container,
                  given the components it contains.                
                <see>
                    java.awt.Component#getMaximumSize                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    LayoutManager                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getLayoutAlignmentX" type="float" line="32"/>
            <javadoc line="32">
                Returns the alignment along the x axis.  This specifies how
                  the component would like to be aligned relative to other
                  components.  The value should be a number between 0 and 1
                  where 0 represents alignment along the origin, 1 is aligned
                  the furthest away from the origin, 0.5 is centered, etc.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getLayoutAlignmentY" type="float" line="40"/>
            <javadoc line="40">
                Returns the alignment along the y axis.  This specifies how
                  the component would like to be aligned relative to other
                  components.  The value should be a number between 0 and 1
                  where 0 represents alignment along the origin, 1 is aligned
                  the furthest away from the origin, 0.5 is centered, etc.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="invalidateLayout" type="void" line="48"/>
            <javadoc line="48">
                Invalidates the layout, indicating that if the layout manager
                  has cached information it should be discarded.                
            </javadoc>
        </interface>
    </source>