<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="com.sun.jmx.snmp.daemon">
        <import package="com.sun.jmx.snmp.SnmpDefinitions"/>
        <import package="com.sun.jmx.snmp.SnmpVarBindList"/>
        <interface name="SnmpInformHandler">
            <implements interface="SnmpDefinitions"/>
            <javadoc line="33">
                Provides the callback methods that are required to be implemented by the application
                  when an inform response is received by the agent.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  Each inform request can be provided with an object that implements this callback
                  interface. An application then uses the SNMP adaptor to start an SNMP inform request,
                  which marks the request as active. The methods in this callback interface
                  get invoked when any of the following happens:
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  &lt;UL&gt;
                  &lt;LI&gt; The agent receives the SNMP inform response.
                  &lt;LI&gt; The agent does not receive any response within a specified time and the number of tries
                  have exceeded the limit (timeout condition).
                  &lt;LI&gt; An internal error occurs while processing or parsing the inform request.
                  &lt;/UL&gt;
                  &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This API is a Sun Microsystems internal API  and is subject
                  to change without notice.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="processSnmpPollData" type="void" line="54"/>
            <javadoc line="54">
                This callback is invoked when a manager responds to an SNMP inform request.
                  The callback should check the error status of the inform request to determine
                  the kind of response.                
                <param>
                    request The <CODE>SnmpInformRequest</CODE> associated with this callback.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    errStatus The status of the request.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    errIndex The index in the list that caused the error.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    vblist The <CODE>Response varBind</CODE> list for the successful request.                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="processSnmpPollTimeout" type="void" line="66"/>
            <javadoc line="66">
                This callback is invoked when a manager does not respond within the
                  specified timeout value to the SNMP inform request. The number of tries have also
                  been exhausted.                
                <param>
                    request The <CODE>SnmpInformRequest</CODE> associated with this callback.                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="processSnmpInternalError" type="void" line="74"/>
            <javadoc line="74">
                This callback is invoked when any form of internal error occurs.                
                <param>
                    request The <CODE>SnmpInformRequest</CODE> associated with this callback.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    errmsg The <CODE>String</CODE> describing the internal error.                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
        </interface>
    </source>