<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="java.lang.management">
        <interface name="BufferPoolMXBean">
            <implements interface="PlatformManagedObject"/>
            <javadoc line="2">
                The management interface for a buffer pool, for example a pool of{@link java.nio.ByteBuffer#allocateDirect direct} or {@link java.nio.MappedByteBuffer mapped} buffers.
                  &lt;p&gt; A class implementing this interface is an{@link javax.management.MXBean}. A Java
                  virtual machine has one or more implementations of this interface. The {@link java.lang.management.ManagementFactory#getPlatformMXBeans getPlatformMXBeans}method can be used to obtain the list of {@code BufferPoolMXBean} objects
                  representing the management interfaces for pools of buffers as follows:
                  &lt;pre&gt;
                  List&amp;lt;BufferPoolMXBean&amp;gt; pools = ManagementFactory.getPlatformMXBeans(BufferPoolMXBean.class);
                  &lt;/pre&gt;
                  &lt;p&gt; The management interfaces are also registered with the platform {@link javax.management.MBeanServer MBeanServer}. The {@link javax.management.ObjectName ObjectName} that uniquely identifies the
                  management interface within the {@code MBeanServer} takes the form:
                  &lt;pre&gt;
                  java.nio:type=BufferPool,name=&lt;i&gt;pool name&lt;/i&gt;
                  &lt;/pre&gt;
                  where &lt;em&gt;pool name&lt;/em&gt; is the {@link #getName name} of the buffer pool.                
                <since>
                    1.7                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getName" type="String" line="19"/>
            <javadoc line="19">
                Returns the name representing this buffer pool.                
                <return>
                    The name of this buffer pool.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getCount" type="long" line="24"/>
            <javadoc line="24">
                Returns an estimate of the number of buffers in the pool.                
                <return>
                    An estimate of the number of buffers in this pool                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getTotalCapacity" type="long" line="29"/>
            <javadoc line="29">
                Returns an estimate of the total capacity of the buffers in this pool.
                  A buffer&apos;s capacity is the number of elements it contains and the value
                  returned by this method is an estimate of the total capacity of buffers
                  in the pool in bytes.                
                <return>
                    An estimate of the total capacity of the buffers in this pool
                      in bytes                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getMemoryUsed" type="long" line="38"/>
            <javadoc line="38">
                Returns an estimate of the memory that the Java virtual machine is using
                  for this buffer pool. The value returned by this method may differ
                  from the estimate of the total {@link #getTotalCapacity capacity} of
                  the buffers in this pool. This difference is explained by alignment,
                  memory allocator, and other implementation specific reasons.                
                <return>
                    An estimate of the memory that the Java virtual machine is using
                      for this buffer pool in bytes, or {@code -1L} if an estimate of
                      the memory usage is not available                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
        </interface>
    </source>