<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="java.sql">
        <interface name="Ref">
            <javadoc line="28">
                The mapping in the Java programming language of an SQL &lt;code&gt;REF&lt;/code&gt;
                  value, which is a reference to an SQL structured type value in the database.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  SQL &lt;code&gt;REF&lt;/code&gt; values are stored in a table that contains
                  instances of a referenceable SQL structured type, and each &lt;code&gt;REF&lt;/code&gt;
                  value is a unique identifier for one instance in that table.
                  An SQL &lt;code&gt;REF&lt;/code&gt; value may be used in place of the
                  SQL structured type it references, either as a column value in a
                  table or an attribute value in a structured type.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  Because an SQL &lt;code&gt;REF&lt;/code&gt; value is a logical pointer to an
                  SQL structured type, a &lt;code&gt;Ref&lt;/code&gt; object is by default also a logical
                  pointer. Thus, retrieving an SQL &lt;code&gt;REF&lt;/code&gt; value as
                  a &lt;code&gt;Ref&lt;/code&gt; object does not materialize
                  the attributes of the structured type on the client.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  A &lt;code&gt;Ref&lt;/code&gt; object can be stored in the database using the
                  &lt;code&gt;PreparedStatement.setRef&lt;/code&gt; method.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  All methods on the &lt;code&gt;Ref&lt;/code&gt; interface must be fully implemented if the
                  JDBC driver supports the data type.                
                <see>
                    Struct                    
                </see>
                <since>
                    1.2                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getBaseTypeName" type="String" line="56"/>
            <javadoc line="56">
                Retrieves the fully-qualified SQL name of the SQL structured type that
                  this &lt;code&gt;Ref&lt;/code&gt; object references.                
                <return>
                    the fully-qualified SQL name of the referenced SQL structured type                    
                </return>
                <exception>
                    SQLException if a database access error occurs                    
                </exception>
                <exception>
                    SQLFeatureNotSupportedException if the JDBC driver does not support
                      this method                    
                </exception>
                <since>
                    1.2                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getObject" type="Object" line="68"/>
            <javadoc line="68">
                Retrieves the referenced object and maps it to a Java type
                  using the given type map.                
                <param>
                    map a &lt;code&gt;java.util.Map&lt;/code&gt; object that contains
                      the mapping to use (the fully-qualified name of the SQL
                      structured type being referenced and the class object for
                      &lt;code&gt;SQLData&lt;/code&gt; implementation to which the SQL
                      structured type will be mapped)                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    a Java &lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt; that is the custom mapping for
                      the SQL structured type to which this &lt;code&gt;Ref&lt;/code&gt;
                      object refers                    
                </return>
                <exception>
                    SQLException if a database access error occurs                    
                </exception>
                <exception>
                    SQLFeatureNotSupportedException if the JDBC driver does not support
                      this method                    
                </exception>
                <since>
                    1.4                    
                </since>
                <see>
                    #setObject                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getObject" type="Object" line="89"/>
            <javadoc line="89">
                Retrieves the SQL structured type instance referenced by
                  this &lt;code&gt;Ref&lt;/code&gt; object.  If the connection&apos;s type map has an entry
                  for the structured type, the instance will be custom mapped to
                  the Java class indicated in the type map.  Otherwise, the
                  structured type instance will be mapped to a &lt;code&gt;Struct&lt;/code&gt; object.                
                <return>
                    a Java &lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt; that is the mapping for
                      the SQL structured type to which this &lt;code&gt;Ref&lt;/code&gt;
                      object refers                    
                </return>
                <exception>
                    SQLException if a database access error occurs                    
                </exception>
                <exception>
                    SQLFeatureNotSupportedException if the JDBC driver does not support
                      this method                    
                </exception>
                <since>
                    1.4                    
                </since>
                <see>
                    #setObject                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="setObject" type="void" line="107"/>
            <javadoc line="107">
                Sets the structured type value that this &lt;code&gt;Ref&lt;/code&gt;
                  object references to the given instance of &lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;.
                  The driver converts this to an SQL structured type when it
                  sends it to the database.                
                <param>
                    value an &lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt; representing the SQL
                      structured type instance that this
                      &lt;code&gt;Ref&lt;/code&gt; object will reference                    
                </param>
                <exception>
                    SQLException if a database access error occurs                    
                </exception>
                <exception>
                    SQLFeatureNotSupportedException if the JDBC driver does not support
                      this method                    
                </exception>
                <since>
                    1.4                    
                </since>
                <see>
                    #getObject()                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    #getObject(Map)                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    PreparedStatement#setObject(int,Object)                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    CallableStatement#setObject(String,Object)                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
        </interface>
    </source>