<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="javax.naming.ldap">
        <class name="SortKey" line="2">
            <javadoc line="2">
                A sort key and its associated sort parameters.
                  This class implements a sort key which is used by the LDAPv3
                  Control for server-side sorting of search results as defined in
                  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc2891.txt&quot;&gt;RFC 2891&lt;/a&gt;.                
                <since>
                    1.5                    
                </since>
                <see>
                    SortControl                    
                </see>
                <author>
                    Vincent Ryan                    
                </author>
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="attrID" type="String" line="12"/>
            <declaration name="reverseOrder" type="boolean" line="13"/>
            <declaration name="matchingRuleID" type="String" line="14"/>
            <javadoc line="15">
                Creates the default sort key for an attribute. Entries will be sorted
                  according to the specified attribute in ascending order using the
                  ordering matching rule defined for use with that attribute.                
                <param>
                    attrID  The non-null ID of the attribute to be used as a sort
                      key.                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="SortKey" type="constructor" line="22">
                <params>
                    <param name="attrID" type="String"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="25">
                Creates a sort key for an attribute. Entries will be sorted according to
                  the specified attribute in the specified sort order and using the
                  specified matching rule, if supplied.                
                <param>
                    attrID          The non-null ID of the attribute to be used as
                      a sort key.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    ascendingOrder  If true then entries are arranged in ascending
                      order. Otherwise there are arranged in
                      descending order.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    matchingRuleID  The possibly null ID of the matching rule to
                      use to order the attribute values. If not
                      specified then the ordering matching rule
                      defined for the sort key attribute is used.                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="SortKey" type="constructor" line="39">
                <params>
                    <param name="attrID" type="String"/>
                    <param name="ascendingOrder" type="boolean"/>
                    <param name="matchingRuleID" type="String"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="44">
                Retrieves the attribute ID of the sort key.                
                <return>
                    The non-null Attribute ID of the sort key.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getAttributeID" type="String" line="48"/>
            <javadoc line="51">
                Determines the sort order.                
                <return>
                    true if the sort order is ascending, false if descending.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="isAscending" type="boolean" line="55"/>
            <javadoc line="58">
                Retrieves the matching rule ID used to order the attribute values.                
                <return>
                    The possibly null matching rule ID. If null then the
                      ordering matching rule defined for the sort key attribute
                      is used.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getMatchingRuleID" type="String" line="64"/>
        </class>
    </source>