<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="javax.swing">
        <javadoc line="28">
            An enumeration for keys used as client properties within the Swing
              implementation.
              &lt;p&gt;
              This enum holds only a small subset of the keys currently used within Swing,
              but we may move more of them here in the future.
              &lt;p&gt;
              Adding an item to, and using, this class instead of {@code String} for
              client properties protects against conflicts with developer-set client
              properties. Using this class also avoids a problem with {@code StringBuilder}and {@code StringBuffer} keys, whereby the keys are not recognized upon
              deserialization.
              &lt;p&gt;
              When a client property value associated with one of these keys does not
              implement {@code Serializable}, the result during serialization depends
              on how the key is defined here. Historically, client properties with values
              not implementing {@code Serializable} have simply been dropped and left out
              of the serialized representation. To define keys with such behavior in this
              enum, provide a value of {@code false} for the {@code reportValueNotSerializable}property. When migrating existing properties to this enum, one may wish to
              consider using this by default, to preserve backward compatibility.
              &lt;p&gt;
              To instead have a {@code NotSerializableException} thrown when a{@code non-Serializable} property is encountered, provide the value of{@code true} for the {@code reportValueNotSerializable} property. This
              is useful when the property represents something that the developer
              needs to know about when it cannot be serialized.            
            <author>
                Shannon Hickey                
            </author>
        </javadoc>
        <javadoc line="60">
            Key used by JComponent for storing InputVerifier.            
        </javadoc>
        <javadoc line="65">
            Key used by JComponent for storing TransferHandler.            
        </javadoc>
        <javadoc line="70">
            Key used by JComponent for storing AncestorNotifier.            
        </javadoc>
        <javadoc line="75">
            Key used by PopupFactory to force heavy weight popups for a
              component.            
        </javadoc>
        <declaration name="reportValueNotSerializable" type="boolean" line="82"/>
        <javadoc line="82">
            Whether or not a {@code NotSerializableException} should be thrown
              during serialization, when the value associated with this key does
              not implement {@code Serializable}.            
        </javadoc>
        <javadoc line="89">
            Constructs a key with the {@code reportValueNotSerializable} property
              set to {@code false}.            
        </javadoc>
        <method name="ClientPropertyKey" type="constructor" line="93"/>
        <javadoc line="97">
            Constructs a key with the {@code reportValueNotSerializable} property
              set to the given value.            
        </javadoc>
        <method name="ClientPropertyKey" type="constructor" line="101">
            <params>
                <param name="reportValueNotSerializable" type="boolean"/>
            </params>
        </method>
        <javadoc line="105">
            Returns whether or not a {@code NotSerializableException} should be thrown
              during serialization, when the value associated with this key does
              not implement {@code Serializable}.            
        </javadoc>
        <method name="getReportValueNotSerializable" type="boolean" line="110"/>
    </source>