<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="javax.swing">
        <javadoc line="27">
            Drop modes, used to determine the method by which a component
              tracks and indicates a drop location during drag and drop.            
            <author>
                Shannon Hickey                
            </author>
            <see>
                JTable#setDropMode                
            </see>
            <see>
                JList#setDropMode                
            </see>
            <see>
                JTree#setDropMode                
            </see>
            <see>
                javax.swing.text.JTextComponent#setDropMode                
            </see>
            <since>
                1.6                
            </since>
        </javadoc>
        <javadoc line="40">
            A component&apos;s own internal selection mechanism (or caret for text
              components) should be used to track the drop location.            
        </javadoc>
        <javadoc line="46">
            The drop location should be tracked in terms of the index of
              existing items. Useful for dropping on items in tables, lists,
              and trees.            
        </javadoc>
        <javadoc line="53">
            The drop location should be tracked in terms of the position
              where new data should be inserted. For components that manage
              a list of items (list and tree for example), the drop location
              should indicate the index where new data should be inserted.
              For text components the location should represent a position
              between characters. For components that manage tabular data
              (table for example), the drop location should indicate
              where to insert new rows, columns, or both, to accommodate
              the dropped data.            
        </javadoc>
        <javadoc line="66">
            The drop location should be tracked in terms of the row index
              where new rows should be inserted to accommodate the dropped
              data. This is useful for components that manage tabular data.            
        </javadoc>
        <javadoc line="73">
            The drop location should be tracked in terms of the column index
              where new columns should be inserted to accommodate the dropped
              data. This is useful for components that manage tabular data.            
        </javadoc>
        <javadoc line="80">
            This mode is a combination of &lt;code&gt;ON&lt;/code&gt;
              and &lt;code&gt;INSERT&lt;/code&gt;, specifying that data can be
              dropped on existing items, or in insert locations
              as specified by &lt;code&gt;INSERT&lt;/code&gt;.            
        </javadoc>
        <javadoc line="88">
            This mode is a combination of &lt;code&gt;ON&lt;/code&gt;
              and &lt;code&gt;INSERT_ROWS&lt;/code&gt;, specifying that data can be
              dropped on existing items, or as insert rows
              as specified by &lt;code&gt;INSERT_ROWS&lt;/code&gt;.            
        </javadoc>
        <javadoc line="96">
            This mode is a combination of &lt;code&gt;ON&lt;/code&gt;
              and &lt;code&gt;INSERT_COLS&lt;/code&gt;, specifying that data can be
              dropped on existing items, or as insert columns
              as specified by &lt;code&gt;INSERT_COLS&lt;/code&gt;.            
        </javadoc>
    </source>