<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<source package="org.ejml">
  <class name="EjmlParameters" startLine="22">
    <javadoc>
      <text>* This is a list of parameters that are used across the code.  To tune performance
 * for a particular system change these values.</text>
      <author>Peter Abeles</author>
    </javadoc>
    <javadoc>
      <text>* Used to adjust which algorithms are used.  Often there is a trade off between memory usage
 * and speed.</text>
    </javadoc>
    <declaration type="MemoryUsage" name="MEMORY" />
    <javadoc>
      <text>* <p>
 * In modern computers there are high speed memory caches.  It is assumed that a square
 * block with this width can be contained entirely in one of those caches.  Settings this
 * value too large can have a dramatic effect on performance in some situations.  Setting
 * it too low results in a less dramatic performance hit.  The optimal value is dependent
 * on the computer's memory architecture.
 * </p></text>
    </javadoc>
    <declaration type="int" name="BLOCK_WIDTH" />
    <declaration type="int" name="BLOCK_WIDTH_CHOL" />
    <javadoc>
      <text>* Number of elements in a block.</text>
    </javadoc>
    <declaration type="int" name="BLOCK_SIZE" />
    <declaration type="int" name="TRANSPOSE_SWITCH" />
    <javadoc>
      <text>* At what point does it switch from a small matrix multiply to the reorder version.</text>
    </javadoc>
    <declaration type="int" name="MULT_COLUMN_SWITCH" />
    <declaration type="int" name="MULT_TRANAB_COLUMN_SWITCH" />
    <declaration type="int" name="MULT_INNER_SWITCH" />
    <javadoc>
      <text>* <p>
 * At which point should it switch to the block cholesky algorithm.
 * </p>
 * <p>
 * In benchmarks  the basic actually performed slightly better at 1000
 * but in JVM 1.6 it some times get stuck in a mode where the basic version was very slow
 * in that case the block performed much better.
 * </p></text>
    </javadoc>
    <declaration type="int" name="SWITCH_BLOCK64_CHOLESKY" />
    <declaration type="int" name="SWITCH_BLOCK64_QR" />
    <javadoc>
      <text>* Use lower memory algorithm while not totally sacrificing speed.</text>
    </javadoc>
    <javadoc>
      <text>* Always favor faster algorithms even if they use more memory.</text>
    </javadoc>
    <comment>See design notes</comment>
  </class>
</source>
