<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="java.awt.image">
        <class name="LookupTable" line="29">
            <extends class="Object"/>
            <javadoc line="29">
                This abstract class defines a lookup table object.  ByteLookupTable
                  and ShortLookupTable are subclasses, which
                  contain byte and short data, respectively.  A lookup table
                  contains data arrays for one or more bands (or components) of an image
                  (for example, separate arrays for R, G, and B),
                  and it contains an offset which will be subtracted from the
                  input values before indexing into the arrays.  This allows an array
                  smaller than the native data size to be provided for a
                  constrained input.  If there is only one array in the lookup
                  table, it will be applied to all bands.  All arrays must be the
                  same size.                
                <see>
                    ByteLookupTable                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    ShortLookupTable                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    LookupOp                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="numComponents" type="int" line="48"/>
            <javadoc line="48">
                Constants                
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="offset" type="int" line="53"/>
            <declaration name="numEntries" type="int" line="54"/>
            <javadoc line="56">
                Constructs a new LookupTable from the number of components and an offset
                  into the lookup table.                
                <param>
                    offset the offset to subtract from input values before indexing
                      into the data arrays for this <code>LookupTable</code>                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    numComponents the number of data arrays in this
                      <code>LookupTable</code>                    
                </param>
                <throws>
                    IllegalArgumentException if <code>offset</code> is less than 0
                      or if <code>numComponents</code> is less than 1                    
                </throws>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="LookupTable" type="constructor" line="66">
                <params>
                    <param name="offset" type="int"/>
                    <param name="numComponents" type="int"/>
                </params>
                <scope line="67"/>
                <scope line="71"/>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="79">
                Returns the number of components in the lookup table.                
                <return>
                    the number of components in this <code>LookupTable</code>.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getNumComponents" type="int" line="83"/>
            <javadoc line="87">
                Returns the offset.                
                <return>
                    the offset of this <code>LookupTable</code>.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getOffset" type="int" line="91"/>
            <method name="lookupPixel" type="int[]" line="95"/>
            <javadoc line="95">
                Returns an &lt;code&gt;int&lt;/code&gt; array of components for
                  one pixel.  The &lt;code&gt;dest&lt;/code&gt; array contains the
                  result of the lookup and is returned.  If dest is
                  &lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;, a new array is allocated.  The
                  source and destination can be equal.                
                <param>
                    src the source array of components of one pixel                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    dest the destination array of components for one pixel,
                      translated with this <code>LookupTable</code>                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    an <code>int</code> array of components for one
                      pixel.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
        </class>
    </source>