<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="java.awt.image">
        <import package="java.awt.Point"/>
        <interface name="WritableRenderedImage">
            <implements interface="RenderedImage"/>
            <javadoc line="3">
                WriteableRenderedImage is a common interface for objects which
                  contain or can produce image data in the form of Rasters and
                  which can be modified and/or written over.  The image
                  data may be stored/produced as a single tile or a regular array
                  of tiles.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  WritableRenderedImage provides notification to other interested
                  objects when a tile is checked out for writing (via the
                  getWritableTile method) and when the last writer of a particular
                  tile relinquishes its access (via a call to releaseWritableTile).
                  Additionally, it allows any caller to determine whether any tiles
                  are currently checked out (via hasTileWriters), and to obtain a
                  list of such tiles (via getWritableTileIndices, in the form of a Vector
                  of Point objects).
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  Objects wishing to be notified of changes in tile writability must
                  implement the TileObserver interface, and are added by a
                  call to addTileObserver.  Multiple calls to
                  addTileObserver for the same object will result in multiple
                  notifications.  An existing observer may reduce its notifications
                  by calling removeTileObserver; if the observer had no
                  notifications the operation is a no-op.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  It is necessary for a WritableRenderedImage to ensure that
                  notifications occur only when the first writer acquires a tile and
                  the last writer releases it.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="addTileObserver" type="void" line="32"/>
            <javadoc line="32">
                Adds an observer.  If the observer is already present,
                  it will receive multiple notifications.                
                <param>
                    to the specified <code>TileObserver</code>                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="removeTileObserver" type="void" line="38"/>
            <javadoc line="38">
                Removes an observer.  If the observer was not registered,
                  nothing happens.  If the observer was registered for multiple
                  notifications, it will now be registered for one fewer.                
                <param>
                    to the specified <code>TileObserver</code>                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getWritableTile" type="WritableRaster" line="45"/>
            <javadoc line="45">
                Checks out a tile for writing.
                  The WritableRenderedImage is responsible for notifying all
                  of its TileObservers when a tile goes from having
                  no writers to having one writer.                
                <param>
                    tileX the X index of the tile.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    tileY the Y index of the tile.                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    a writable tile.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="releaseWritableTile" type="void" line="55"/>
            <javadoc line="55">
                Relinquishes the right to write to a tile.  If the caller
                  continues to write to the tile, the results are undefined.
                  Calls to this method should only appear in matching pairs
                  with calls to getWritableTile; any other use will lead
                  to undefined results.
                  The WritableRenderedImage is responsible for notifying all of
                  its TileObservers when a tile goes from having one writer
                  to having no writers.                
                <param>
                    tileX the X index of the tile.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    tileY the Y index of the tile.                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="isTileWritable" type="boolean" line="68"/>
            <javadoc line="68">
                Returns whether a tile is currently checked out for writing.                
                <param>
                    tileX the X index of the tile.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    tileY the Y index of the tile.                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    <code>true</code> if specified tile is checked out
                      for writing; <code>false</code> otherwise.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getWritableTileIndices" type="Point[]" line="76"/>
            <javadoc line="76">
                Returns an array of Point objects indicating which tiles
                  are checked out for writing.  Returns null if none are
                  checked out.                
                <return>
                    an array containing the locations of tiles that are
                      checked out for writing.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="hasTileWriters" type="boolean" line="84"/>
            <javadoc line="84">
                Returns whether any tile is checked out for writing.
                  Semantically equivalent to (getWritableTileIndices() != null).                
                <return>
                    <code>true</code> if any tiles are checked out for
                      writing; <code>false</code> otherwise.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="setData" type="void" line="91"/>
            <javadoc line="91">
                Sets a rect of the image to the contents of the Raster r, which is
                  assumed to be in the same coordinate space as the WritableRenderedImage.
                  The operation is clipped to the bounds of the WritableRenderedImage.                
                <param>
                    r the specified <code>Raster</code>                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
        </interface>
    </source>