<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="javax.sound.midi">
        <class name="Patch" line="29">
            <javadoc line="29">
                A &lt;code&gt;Patch&lt;/code&gt; object represents a location, on a MIDI
                  synthesizer, into which a single instrument is stored (loaded).
                  Every &lt;code&gt;Instrument&lt;/code&gt; object has its own &lt;code&gt;Patch&lt;/code&gt;
                  object that specifies the memory location
                  into which that instrument should be loaded. The
                  location is specified abstractly by a bank index and a program number (not by
                  any scheme that directly refers to a specific address or offset in RAM).
                  This is a hierarchical indexing scheme: MIDI provides for up to 16384 banks,
                  each of which contains up to 128 program locations.  For example, a
                  minimal sort of synthesizer might have only one bank of instruments, and
                  only 32 instruments (programs) in that bank.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  To select what instrument should play the notes on a particular MIDI
                  channel, two kinds of MIDI message are used that specify a patch location:
                  a bank-select command, and a program-change channel command.  The Java Sound
                  equivalent is the{@link MidiChannel#programChange(int,int) programChange(int, int)}method of &lt;code&gt;MidiChannel&lt;/code&gt;.                
                <see>
                    Instrument                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    Instrument#getPatch()                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    MidiChannel#programChange(int,int)                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    Synthesizer#loadInstruments(Soundbank,Patch[])                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    Soundbank                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    Sequence#getPatchList()                    
                </see>
                <author>
                    Kara Kytle                    
                </author>
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="bank" type="int" line="62"/>
            <javadoc line="62">
                Bank index                
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="program" type="int" line="68"/>
            <javadoc line="68">
                Program change number                
            </javadoc>
            <javadoc line="74">
                Constructs a new patch object from the specified bank and program
                  numbers.                
                <param>
                    bank the bank index (in the range from 0 to 16383)                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    program the program index (in the range from 0 to 127)                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="Patch" type="constructor" line="80">
                <params>
                    <param name="bank" type="int"/>
                    <param name="program" type="int"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="87">
                Returns the number of the bank that contains the instrument
                  whose location this &lt;code&gt;Patch&lt;/code&gt; specifies.                
                <return>
                    the bank number, whose range is from 0 to 16383                    
                </return>
                <see>
                    MidiChannel#programChange(int,int)                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getBank" type="int" line="93"/>
            <javadoc line="99">
                Returns the index, within
                  a bank, of the instrument whose location this &lt;code&gt;Patch&lt;/code&gt; specifies.                
                <return>
                    the instrument's program number, whose range is from 0 to 127                    
                </return>
                <see>
                    MidiChannel#getProgram                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    MidiChannel#programChange(int)                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    MidiChannel#programChange(int,int)                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getProgram" type="int" line="108"/>
        </class>
    </source>