<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<source package="org.apache.commons.math3.ode">
  <interface name="SecondOrderDifferentialEquations" startLine="21">
    <javadoc>
      <text>* This interface represents a second order differential equations set.
 * <p>This interface should be implemented by all real second order
 * differential equation problems before they can be handled by the
 * integrators {@link SecondOrderIntegrator#integrate} method.</p>
 * <p>A second order differential equations problem, as seen by an
 * integrator is the second time derivative <code>d2Y/dt^2</code> of a
 * state vector <code>Y</code>, both being one dimensional
 * arrays. From the integrator point of view, this derivative depends
 * only on the current time <code>t</code>, on the state vector
 * <code>Y</code> and on the first time derivative of the state
 * vector.</p>
 * <p>For real problems, the derivative depends also on parameters
 * that do not belong to the state vector (dynamical model constants
 * for example). These constants are completely outside of the scope
 * of this interface, the classes that implement it are allowed to
 * handle them as they want.</p></text>
      <see>SecondOrderIntegrator</see>
      <see>FirstOrderConverter</see>
      <see>FirstOrderDifferentialEquations</see>
      <version>$Id: SecondOrderDifferentialEquations.java 1416643 2012-12-03 19:37:14Z tn $</version>
      <since>1.2</since>
    </javadoc>
    <method name="getDimension" type="int" startLine="50" endLine="53" />
    <javadoc>
      <text>* Get the dimension of the problem.</text>
      <return>dimension of the problem</return>
    </javadoc>
    <method name="computeSecondDerivatives" type="void" startLine="55" endLine="63" />
    <javadoc>
      <text>* Get the current time derivative of the state vector.</text>
      <param>t current value of the independent <I>time</I> variable</param>
      <param>y array containing the current value of the state vector</param>
      <param>yDot array containing the current value of the first derivative
 * of the state vector</param>
      <param>yDDot placeholder array where to put the second time derivative
 * of the state vector</param>
    </javadoc>
  </interface>
</source>
