<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="javax.print.attribute">
        <interface name="PrintJobAttributeSet">
            <implements interface="AttributeSet"/>
            <javadoc line="2">
                Interface PrintJobAttributeSet specifies the interface for a set of print
                  job attributes, i.e. printing attributes that implement interface {@link PrintJobAttribute PrintJobAttribute}. In the Print Service API, a
                  service uses a PrintJobAttributeSet to report the status of a print job.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  A PrintJobAttributeSet is just an {@link AttributeSet AttributeSet} whose
                  constructors and mutating operations guarantee an additional invariant,
                  namely that all attribute values in the PrintJobAttributeSet must be
                  instances of interface {@link PrintJobAttribute PrintJobAttribute}.
                  The {@link #add(Attribute) &lt;CODE&gt;add(Attribute)&lt;/CODE&gt;}, and{@link #addAll(AttributeSet) &lt;CODE&gt;addAll(AttributeSet)&lt;/CODE&gt;} operations
                  are respecified below to guarantee this additional invariant.
                  &lt;P&gt;                
                <author>
                    Alan Kaminsky                    
                </author>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="add" type="boolean" line="17"/>
            <javadoc line="17">
                Adds the specified attribute value to this attribute set if it is not
                  already present, first removing any existing value in the same
                  attribute category as the specified attribute value (optional
                  operation).                
                <param>
                    attribute  Attribute value to be added to this attribute set.                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    <tt>true</tt> if this attribute set changed as a result of
                      the call, i.e., the given attribute value was not already a
                      member of this attribute set.                    
                </return>
                <throws>
                    UnmodifiableSetException(unchecked exception) Thrown if this attribute set does not
                      support the <CODE>add()</CODE> operation.                    
                </throws>
                <throws>
                    ClassCastException(unchecked exception) Thrown if the <CODE>attribute</CODE> is
                      not an instance of interface{@link PrintJobAttribute PrintJobAttribute}.                    
                </throws>
                <throws>
                    NullPointerException(unchecked exception) Thrown if the <CODE>attribute</CODE> is null.                    
                </throws>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="addAll" type="boolean" line="33"/>
            <javadoc line="33">
                Adds all of the elements in the specified set to this attribute.
                  The outcome is  the same as if the{@link #add(Attribute) &lt;CODE&gt;add(Attribute)&lt;/CODE&gt;}operation had been applied to this attribute set successively with
                  each element from the specified set. If none of the categories in the
                  specified set  are the same as any categories in this attribute set,
                  the &lt;tt&gt;addAll()&lt;/tt&gt; operation effectively modifies this attribute
                  set so that its value is the &lt;i&gt;union&lt;/i&gt; of the two sets.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  The behavior of the &lt;CODE&gt;addAll()&lt;/CODE&gt; operation is unspecified if
                  the specified set is modified while the operation is in progress.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  If the &lt;CODE&gt;addAll()&lt;/CODE&gt; operation throws an exception, the effect
                  on this attribute set&apos;s state is implementation dependent; elements
                  from the specified set before the point of the exception may or
                  may not have been added to this attribute set.                
                <param>
                    attributes  whose elements are to be added to this attribute
                      set.                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    <tt>true</tt> if this attribute set changed as a result of
                      the call.                    
                </return>
                <throws>
                    UnmodifiableSetException(Unchecked exception) Thrown if this attribute set does not
                      support the <tt>addAll()</tt> method.                    
                </throws>
                <throws>
                    ClassCastException(Unchecked exception) Thrown if some element in the specified
                      set is not an instance of interface {@link PrintJobAttributePrintJobAttribute}.                    
                </throws>
                <throws>
                    NullPointerException(Unchecked exception) Thrown if the specified  set is null.                    
                </throws>
                <see>
                    #add(Attribute)                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
        </interface>
    </source>