<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="java.awt.im.spi">
        <import package="java.awt.AWTException"/>
        <import package="java.awt.Image"/>
        <import package="java.util.Locale"/>
        <interface name="InputMethodDescriptor">
            <javadoc line="33">
                Defines methods that provide sufficient information about an input method
                  to enable selection and loading of that input method.
                  The input method itself is only loaded when it is actually used.                
                <since>
                    1.3                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getAvailableLocales" type="Locale[]" line="43"/>
            <javadoc line="43">
                Returns the locales supported by the corresponding input method.
                  The locale may describe just the language, or may also include
                  country and variant information if needed.
                  The information is used to select input methods by locale
                  ({@link java.awt.im.InputContext#selectInputMethod(Locale)}). It may also
                  be used to sort input methods by locale in a user-visible
                  list of input methods.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  Only the input method&apos;s primary locales should be returned.
                  For example, if a Japanese input method also has a pass-through
                  mode for Roman characters, typically still only Japanese would
                  be returned. Thus, the list of locales returned is typically
                  a subset of the locales for which the corresponding input method&apos;s
                  implementation of {@link java.awt.im.spi.InputMethod#setLocale} returns true.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  If {@link #hasDynamicLocaleList} returns true, this method is
                  called each time the information is needed. This
                  gives input methods that depend on network resources the chance
                  to add or remove locales as resources become available or
                  unavailable.                
                <return>
                    the locales supported by the input method                    
                </return>
                <exception>
                    AWTException if it can be determined that the input method
                      is inoperable, for example, because of incomplete installation.                    
                </exception>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="hasDynamicLocaleList" type="boolean" line="71"/>
            <javadoc line="71">
                Returns whether the list of available locales can change
                  at runtime. This may be the case, for example, for adapters
                  that access real input methods over the network.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getInputMethodDisplayName" type="String" line="78"/>
            <javadoc line="78">
                Returns the user-visible name of the corresponding
                  input method for the given input locale in the language in which
                  the name will be displayed.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  The inputLocale parameter specifies the locale for which text
                  is input.
                  This parameter can only take values obtained from this descriptor&apos;s{@link #getAvailableLocales} method or null. If it is null, an
                  input locale independent name for the input method should be
                  returned.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  If a name for the desired display language is not available, the
                  method may fall back to some other language.                
                <param>
                    inputLocale the locale for which text input is supported, or null                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    displayLanguage the language in which the name will be displayed                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getInputMethodIcon" type="Image" line="98"/>
            <javadoc line="98">
                Returns an icon for the corresponding input method.
                  The icon may be used by a user interface for selecting input methods.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  The inputLocale parameter specifies the locale for which text
                  is input.
                  This parameter can only take values obtained from this descriptor&apos;s{@link #getAvailableLocales} method or null. If it is null, an
                  input locale independent icon for the input method should be
                  returned.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  The icon&apos;s size should be 16&amp;times;16 pixels.                
                <param>
                    inputLocale the locale for which text input is supported, or null                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    an icon for the corresponding input method, or null                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="createInputMethod" type="InputMethod" line="116"/>
            <javadoc line="116">
                Creates a new instance of the corresponding input method.                
                <return>
                    a new instance of the corresponding input method                    
                </return>
                <exception>
                    Exception any exception that may occur while creating the
                      input method instance                    
                </exception>
            </javadoc>
        </interface>
    </source>