<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="sun.jvmstat.monitor.event">
        <import package="java.util.Set"/>
        <import package="sun.jvmstat.monitor.MonitoredHost"/>
        <class name="VmStatusChangeEvent" line="31">
            <extends class="HostEvent"/>
            <javadoc line="31">
                Provides a description of a change in status of the Java Virtual Machines
                  associated with a MonitoredHost.                
                <author>
                    Brian Doherty                    
                </author>
                <since>
                    1.5                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="active" type="Set" line="40"/>
            <javadoc line="40">
                The set of currently active Java Virtual Machines for the MonitoredHost.
                  The set contains an Integer object holding the &lt;em&gt;lvmid&lt;/em&gt; for each
                  active Java Virtual Machine on the MonitoredHost. This Set will only
                  contain Integer objects.                
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="started" type="Set" line="48"/>
            <javadoc line="48">
                The set of Java Virtual Machines started on MonitoredHost since the
                  previous event. The set contains an Integer object holding the
                  &lt;em&gt;lvmid&lt;/em&gt; for each Java Virtual Machine started on the
                  MonitoredHost. This Set will only contain Integer objects.                
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="terminated" type="Set" line="56"/>
            <javadoc line="56">
                The set of Java Virtual Machines terminated on MonitoredHost since the
                  previous event. The set contains an Integer object holding the
                  &lt;em&gt;lvmid&lt;/em&gt; for each Java Virtual Machine started on the
                  MonitoredHost. This Set will only contain Integer objects.                
            </javadoc>
            <javadoc line="64">
                Construct a new VmStatusChangeEvent instance.                
                <param>
                    host the MonitoredHost that is the source of the event.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    active the set of currently active Java Virtual Machines                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    started the set of Java Virtual Machines started since the
                      last event.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    terminated the set of Java Virtual Machines terminated since
                      the last event.                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="VmStatusChangeEvent" type="constructor" line="75">
                <params>
                    <param name="host" type="MonitoredHost"/>
                    <param name="active" type="Set"/>
                    <param name="started" type="Set"/>
                    <param name="terminated" type="Set"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="82">
                Return the set of currently active Java Virtual Machines.
                  The set contains an Integer object holding the &lt;em&gt;lvmid&lt;/em&gt; for each
                  active Java Virtual Machine on the MonitoredHost.                
                <return>
                    Set - a set of Integer objects containing the <em>lvmid</em>
                      of each active Java Virtual Machine on the host. If
                      there are no active Java Virtual Machines on the host,
                      an empty Set is returned.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getActive" type="Set" line="92"/>
            <javadoc line="96">
                Return the set of Java Virtual Machines started since the last
                  event notification. The set contains an Integer object holding
                  the &lt;em&gt;lvmid&lt;/em&gt; for each Java Virtual Machine started on the
                  MonitoredHost since the last event notification.                
                <return>
                    Set - a set of Integer objects containing the <em>lvmid</em>
                      of each Java Virtual Machine started on the host. If
                      no Java Virtual Machines were recently started on the
                      host, an empty Set is returned.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getStarted" type="Set" line="107"/>
            <javadoc line="111">
                Return the set of Java Virtual Machines terminated since the last
                  event notification. The set contains an Integer object holding
                  the &lt;em&gt;lvmid&lt;/em&gt; for each Java Virtual Machine terminated on the
                  MonitoredHost since the last event notification.                
                <return>
                    Set - a set of Integer objects containing the <em>lvmid</em>
                      of each Java Virtual Machine terminated on the host. If
                      no Java Virtual Machines were recently terminated on the
                      host, an empty Set is returned.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getTerminated" type="Set" line="122"/>
        </class>
    </source>