<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="javax.sound.sampled">
        <class name="ReverbType" line="29">
            <javadoc line="29">
                The &lt;code&gt;ReverbType&lt;/code&gt; class provides methods for
                  accessing various reverberation settings to be applied to
                  an audio signal.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  Reverberation simulates the reflection of sound off of
                  the walls, ceiling, and floor of a room.  Depending on
                  the size of the room, and how absorbent or reflective the materials in the
                  room&apos;s surfaces are, the sound might bounce around for a
                  long time before dying away.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  The reverberation parameters provided by &lt;code&gt;ReverbType&lt;/code&gt; consist
                  of the delay time and intensity of early reflections, the delay time and
                  intensity of late reflections, and an overall decay time.
                  Early reflections are the initial individual low-order reflections of the
                  direct signal off the surfaces in the room.
                  The late Relections are the dense, high-order reflections that characterize
                  the room&apos;s reverberation.
                  The delay times for the start of these two reflection types give the listener
                  a sense of the overall size and complexity of the room&apos;s shape and contents.
                  The larger the room, the longer the reflection delay times.
                  The early and late reflections&apos; intensities define the gain (in decibels) of the reflected
                  signals as compared to the direct signal.  These intensities give the
                  listener an impression of the absorptive nature of the surfaces and objects
                  in the room.
                  The decay time defines how long the reverberation takes to exponentially
                  decay until it is no longer perceptible (&quot;effective zero&quot;).
                  The larger and less absorbent the surfaces, the longer the decay time.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  The set of parameters defined here may not include all aspects of reverberation
                  as specified by some systems.  For example, the Midi Manufacturer&apos;s Association
                  (MMA) has an Interactive Audio Special Interest Group (IASIG), which has a
                  3-D Working Group that has defined a Level 2 Spec (I3DL2).  I3DL2
                  supports filtering of reverberation and
                  control of reverb density.  These properties are not included in the JavaSound 1.0
                  definition of a reverb control.  In such a case, the implementing system
                  should either extend the defined reverb control to include additional
                  parameters, or else interpret the system&apos;s additional capabilities in a way that fits
                  the model described here.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  If implementing JavaSound on a I3DL2-compliant device:
                  &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Filtering is disabled (high-frequency attenuations are set to 0.0 dB)
                  &lt;li&gt;Density parameters are set to midway between minimum and maximum
                  &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  The following table shows what parameter values an implementation might use for a
                  representative set of reverberation settings.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  &lt;b&gt;Reverberation Types and Parameters&lt;/b&gt;
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  &lt;table border=1 cellpadding=5 summary=&quot;reverb types and params: decay time, late intensity, late delay, early intensity, and early delay&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;tr&gt;
                  &lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
                  &lt;th&gt;Decay Time (ms)&lt;/th&gt;
                  &lt;th&gt;Late Intensity (dB)&lt;/th&gt;
                  &lt;th&gt;Late Delay (ms)&lt;/th&gt;
                  &lt;th&gt;Early Intensity (dB)&lt;/th&gt;
                  &lt;th&gt;Early Delay(ms)&lt;/th&gt;
                  &lt;/tr&gt;
                  &lt;tr&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;Cavern&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;2250&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;-2.0&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;41.3&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;-1.4&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;10.3&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;/tr&gt;
                  &lt;tr&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;Dungeon&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;1600&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;-1.0&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;10.3&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;-0.7&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;2.6&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;/tr&gt;
                  &lt;tr&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;Garage&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;900&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;-6.0&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;14.7&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;-4.0&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;3.9&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;/tr&gt;
                  &lt;tr&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;Acoustic Lab&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;280&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;-3.0&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;8.0&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;-2.0&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;2.0&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;/tr&gt;
                  &lt;tr&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;Closet&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;-10.0&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;2.5&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;-7.0&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;0.6&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;/tr&gt;
                  &lt;/table&gt;                
                <author>
                    Kara Kytle                    
                </author>
                <since>
                    1.3                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="name" type="String" line="144"/>
            <javadoc line="144">
                Descriptive name of the reverb type..                
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="earlyReflectionDelay" type="int" line="149"/>
            <javadoc line="149">
                Early reflection delay in microseconds.                
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="earlyReflectionIntensity" type="float" line="154"/>
            <javadoc line="154">
                Early reflection intensity.                
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="lateReflectionDelay" type="int" line="159"/>
            <javadoc line="159">
                Late reflection delay in microseconds.                
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="lateReflectionIntensity" type="float" line="164"/>
            <javadoc line="164">
                Late reflection intensity.                
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="decayTime" type="int" line="169"/>
            <javadoc line="169">
                Total decay time                
            </javadoc>
            <javadoc line="175">
                Constructs a new reverb type that has the specified reverberation
                  parameter values.                
                <param>
                    name the name of the new reverb type, or a zero-length <code>String</code>                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    earlyReflectionDelay the new type's early reflection delay time in microseconds                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    earlyReflectionIntensity the new type's early reflection intensity in dB                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    lateReflectionDelay the new type's late reflection delay time in microseconds                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    lateReflectionIntensity the new type's late reflection intensity in dB                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    decayTime the new type's decay time in microseconds                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="ReverbType" type="constructor" line="185">
                <params>
                    <param name="name" type="String"/>
                    <param name="earlyReflectionDelay" type="int"/>
                    <param name="earlyReflectionIntensity" type="float"/>
                    <param name="lateReflectionDelay" type="int"/>
                    <param name="lateReflectionIntensity" type="float"/>
                    <param name="decayTime" type="int"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="196">
                Obtains the name of this reverb type.                
                <return>
                    the name of this reverb type                    
                </return>
                <since>
                    1.5                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getName" type="String" line="201"/>
            <javadoc line="206">
                Returns the early reflection delay time in microseconds.
                  This is the amount of time between when the direct signal is
                  heard and when the first early reflections are heard.                
                <return>
                    early reflection delay time for this reverb type, in microseconds                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getEarlyReflectionDelay" type="int" line="212"/>
            <javadoc line="217">
                Returns the early reflection intensity in decibels.
                  This is the amplitude attenuation of the first early reflections
                  relative to the direct signal.                
                <return>
                    early reflection intensity for this reverb type, in dB                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getEarlyReflectionIntensity" type="float" line="223"/>
            <javadoc line="228">
                Returns the late reflection delay time in microseconds.
                  This is the amount of time between when the first early reflections
                  are heard and when the first late reflections are heard.                
                <return>
                    late reflection delay time for this reverb type, in microseconds                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getLateReflectionDelay" type="int" line="234"/>
            <javadoc line="239">
                Returns the late reflection intensity in decibels.
                  This is the amplitude attenuation of the first late reflections
                  relative to the direct signal.                
                <return>
                    late reflection intensity for this reverb type, in dB                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getLateReflectionIntensity" type="float" line="245"/>
            <javadoc line="250">
                Obtains the decay time, which is the amount of time over which the
                  late reflections attenuate to effective zero.  The effective zero
                  value is implementation-dependent.                
                <return>
                    the decay time of the late reflections, in microseconds                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getDecayTime" type="int" line="256"/>
            <javadoc line="261">
                Indicates whether the specified object is equal to this reverb type,
                  returning &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; if the objects are identical.                
                <param>
                    obj the reference object with which to compare                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    <code>true</code> if this reverb type is the same as
                      <code>obj</code>; <code>false</code> otherwise                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="equals" type="boolean" line="268">
                <params>
                    <param name="obj" type="Object"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="273">
                Finalizes the hashcode method.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="hashCode" type="int" line="276"/>
            <javadoc line="281">
                Provides a &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; representation of the reverb type,
                  including its name and its parameter settings.
                  The exact contents of the string may vary between implementations of
                  Java Sound.                
                <return>
                    reverberation type name and description                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="toString" type="String" line="288">
                <comment line="291">
                    $$fb2001-07-20: fix for bug 4385060: The &quot;name&quot; attribute of class &quot;ReverbType&quot; is not accessible.
                    return (super.toString() + &quot;, early reflection delay &quot; + earlyReflectionDelay +                    
                </comment>
            </method>
        </class>
    </source>