<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="org.apache.commons.math3.ode">
        <import package="org.apache.commons.math3.exception.DimensionMismatchException"/>
        <import package="org.apache.commons.math3.exception.MaxCountExceededException"/>
        <interface name="SecondaryEquations">
            <javadoc line="23">
                This interface allows users to add secondary differential equations to a primary
                  set of differential equations.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  In some cases users may need to integrate some problem-specific equations along
                  with a primary set of differential equations. One example is optimal control where
                  adjoined parameters linked to the minimized hamiltonian must be integrated.
                  &lt;/p&gt;
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  This interface allows users to add such equations to a primary set of {@link FirstOrderDifferentialEquations first order differential equations}thanks to the {@link ExpandableStatefulODE#addSecondaryEquations(SecondaryEquations)}method.
                  &lt;/p&gt;                
                <see>
                    ExpandableStatefulODE                    
                </see>
                <version>
                    $Id: SecondaryEquations.java 1416643 2012-12-03 19:37:14Z tn $                    
                </version>
                <since>
                    3.0                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getDimension" type="int" line="44"/>
            <javadoc line="44">
                Get the dimension of the secondary state parameters.                
                <return>
                    dimension of the secondary state parameters                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="computeDerivatives" type="void" line="49"/>
            <javadoc line="49">
                Compute the derivatives related to the secondary state parameters.                
                <param>
                    t current value of the independent &lt;I&gt;time&lt;/I&gt; variable                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    primary array containing the current value of the primary state vector                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    primaryDot array containing the derivative of the primary state vector                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    secondary array containing the current value of the secondary state vector                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    secondaryDot placeholder array where to put the derivative of the secondary state vector                    
                </param>
                <exception>
                    MaxCountExceededException if the number of functions evaluations is exceeded                    
                </exception>
                <exception>
                    DimensionMismatchException if arrays dimensions do not match equations settings                    
                </exception>
            </javadoc>
        </interface>
    </source>