<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="javax.management">
        <interface name="DynamicMBean">
            <javadoc line="30">
                Defines the methods that should be implemented by
                  a Dynamic MBean (MBean that exposes a dynamic management interface).                
                <since>
                    1.5                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getAttribute" type="Object" line="39"/>
            <javadoc line="39">
                Obtain the value of a specific attribute of the Dynamic MBean.                
                <param>
                    attribute The name of the attribute to be retrieved                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    The value of the attribute retrieved.                    
                </return>
                <exception>
                    AttributeNotFoundException                    
                </exception>
                <exception>
                    MBeanException  Wraps a &lt;CODE&gt;java.lang.Exception&lt;/CODE&gt; thrown by the MBean&apos;s getter.                    
                </exception>
                <exception>
                    ReflectionException  Wraps a &lt;CODE&gt;java.lang.Exception&lt;/CODE&gt; thrown while trying to invoke the getter.                    
                </exception>
                <see>
                    #setAttribute                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="setAttribute" type="void" line="55"/>
            <javadoc line="55">
                Set the value of a specific attribute of the Dynamic MBean.                
                <param>
                    attribute The identification of the attribute to
                      be set and  the value it is to be set to.                    
                </param>
                <exception>
                    AttributeNotFoundException                    
                </exception>
                <exception>
                    InvalidAttributeValueException                    
                </exception>
                <exception>
                    MBeanException Wraps a &lt;CODE&gt;java.lang.Exception&lt;/CODE&gt; thrown by the MBean&apos;s setter.                    
                </exception>
                <exception>
                    ReflectionException Wraps a &lt;CODE&gt;java.lang.Exception&lt;/CODE&gt; thrown while trying to invoke the MBean&apos;s setter.                    
                </exception>
                <see>
                    #getAttribute                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getAttributes" type="AttributeList" line="71"/>
            <javadoc line="71">
                Get the values of several attributes of the Dynamic MBean.                
                <param>
                    attributes A list of the attributes to be retrieved.                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    The list of attributes retrieved.                    
                </return>
                <see>
                    #setAttributes                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="setAttributes" type="AttributeList" line="82"/>
            <javadoc line="82">
                Sets the values of several attributes of the Dynamic MBean.                
                <param>
                    attributes A list of attributes: The identification of the
                      attributes to be set and  the values they are to be set to.                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    The list of attributes that were set, with their new values.                    
                </return>
                <see>
                    #getAttributes                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="invoke" type="Object" line="94"/>
            <javadoc line="94">
                Allows an action to be invoked on the Dynamic MBean.                
                <param>
                    actionName The name of the action to be invoked.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    params An array containing the parameters to be set when the action is
                      invoked.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    signature An array containing the signature of the action. The class objects will
                      be loaded through the same class loader as the one used for loading the
                      MBean on which the action is invoked.                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    The object returned by the action, which represents the result of
                      invoking the action on the MBean specified.                    
                </return>
                <exception>
                    MBeanException  Wraps a &lt;CODE&gt;java.lang.Exception&lt;/CODE&gt; thrown by the MBean&apos;s invoked method.                    
                </exception>
                <exception>
                    ReflectionException  Wraps a &lt;CODE&gt;java.lang.Exception&lt;/CODE&gt; thrown while trying to invoke the method                    
                </exception>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getMBeanInfo" type="MBeanInfo" line="113"/>
            <javadoc line="113">
                Provides the exposed attributes and actions of the Dynamic MBean using an MBeanInfo object.                
                <return>
                    An instance of &lt;CODE&gt;MBeanInfo&lt;/CODE&gt; allowing all attributes and actions
                      exposed by this Dynamic MBean to be retrieved.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
        </interface>
    </source>