<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="javax.management">
        <import package="javax.management.MBeanException"/>
        <import package="javax.management.RuntimeOperationsException"/>
        <import package="javax.management.InstanceNotFoundException"/>
        <interface name="PersistentMBean">
            <javadoc line="5">
                This class is the interface to be implemented by MBeans that are meant to be
                  persistent.  MBeans supporting this interface should call the load method during
                  construction in order to prime the MBean from the persistent store.
                  In the case of a ModelMBean, the store method should be called by the MBeanServer based on the descriptors in
                  the ModelMBean or by the MBean itself during normal processing of the ModelMBean.                
                <since>
                    1.5                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="load" type="void" line="14"/>
            <javadoc line="14">
                Instantiates thisMBean instance with the data found for
                  the MBean in the persistent store.  The data loaded could include
                  attribute and operation values.
                  This method should be called during construction or initialization of this instance,
                  and before the MBean is registered with the MBeanServer.                
                <exception>
                    MBeanException Wraps another exception or persistence is not supported                    
                </exception>
                <exception>
                    RuntimeOperationsException Wraps exceptions from the persistence mechanism                    
                </exception>
                <exception>
                    InstanceNotFoundException Could not find or load this MBean from persistent
                      storage                    
                </exception>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="store" type="void" line="26"/>
            <javadoc line="26">
                Captures the current state of this MBean instance and
                  writes it out to the persistent store.  The state stored could include
                  attribute and operation values. If one of these methods of persistence is
                  not supported a &quot;serviceNotFound&quot; exception will be thrown.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  Persistence policy from the MBean and attribute descriptor is used to guide execution
                  of this method. The MBean should be stored if &apos;persistPolicy&apos; field is:
                  &lt;PRE&gt;  != &quot;never&quot;
                  = &quot;always&quot;
                  = &quot;onTimer&quot; and now &gt; &apos;lastPersistTime&apos; + &apos;persistPeriod&apos;
                  = &quot;NoMoreOftenThan&quot; and now &gt; &apos;lastPersistTime&apos; + &apos;persistPeriod&apos;
                  = &quot;onUnregister&quot;
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  Do not store the MBean if &apos;persistPolicy&apos; field is:
                  = &quot;never&quot;
                  = &quot;onUpdate&quot;
                  = &quot;onTimer&quot; &amp;&amp; now &lt; &apos;lastPersistTime&apos; + &apos;persistPeriod&apos;
                  &lt;P&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;                
                <exception>
                    MBeanException Wraps another exception or persistence is not supported                    
                </exception>
                <exception>
                    RuntimeOperationsException Wraps exceptions from the persistence mechanism                    
                </exception>
                <exception>
                    InstanceNotFoundException Could not find/access the persistent store                    
                </exception>
            </javadoc>
        </interface>
    </source>