<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="javax.script">
        <import package="java.util.Map"/>
        <class name="CompiledScript" line="3">
            <javadoc line="3">
                Extended by classes that store results of compilations.  State
                  might be stored in the form of Java classes, Java class files or scripting
                  language opcodes.  The script may be executed repeatedly
                  without reparsing.
                  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
                  Each &lt;code&gt;CompiledScript&lt;/code&gt; is associated with a &lt;code&gt;ScriptEngine&lt;/code&gt; -- A call to an  &lt;code&gt;eval&lt;/code&gt;
                  method of the &lt;code&gt;CompiledScript&lt;/code&gt; causes the execution of the script by the
                  &lt;code&gt;ScriptEngine&lt;/code&gt;.  Changes in the state of the &lt;code&gt;ScriptEngine&lt;/code&gt; caused by execution
                  of tne &lt;code&gt;CompiledScript&lt;/code&gt;  may visible during subsequent executions of scripts by the engine.                
                <author>
                    Mike Grogan                    
                </author>
                <since>
                    1.6                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="eval" type="Object" line="17"/>
            <javadoc line="17">
                Executes the program stored in this &lt;code&gt;CompiledScript&lt;/code&gt; object.                
                <param>
                    context A <code>ScriptContext</code> that is used in the same way as
                      the <code>ScriptContext</code> passed to the <code>eval</code> methods of
                      <code>ScriptEngine</code>.                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    The value returned by the script execution, if any.  Should return <code>null</code>
                      if no value is returned by the script execution.                    
                </return>
                <throws>
                    ScriptException if an error occurs.                    
                </throws>
                <throws>
                    NullPointerException if context is null.                    
                </throws>
            </javadoc>
            <javadoc line="28">
                Executes the program stored in the &lt;code&gt;CompiledScript&lt;/code&gt; object using
                  the supplied &lt;code&gt;Bindings&lt;/code&gt; of attributes as the &lt;code&gt;ENGINE_SCOPE&lt;/code&gt; of the
                  associated &lt;code&gt;ScriptEngine&lt;/code&gt; during script execution.  If bindings is null,
                  then the effect of calling this method is same as that of eval(getEngine().getContext()).
                  &lt;p&gt;.
                  The &lt;code&gt;GLOBAL_SCOPE&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;Bindings&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Reader&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Writer&lt;/code&gt;
                  associated with the default &lt;code&gt;ScriptContext&lt;/code&gt; of the associated &lt;code&gt;ScriptEngine&lt;/code&gt; are used.                
                <param>
                    bindings The bindings of attributes used for the <code>ENGINE_SCOPE</code>.                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    The return value from the script execution                    
                </return>
                <throws>
                    ScriptException if an error occurs.                    
                </throws>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="eval" type="Object" line="40">
                <params>
                    <param name="bindings" type="Bindings"/>
                </params>
                <declaration name="ctxt" type="ScriptContext" line="41"/>
                <scope line="42">
                    <declaration name="tempctxt" type="SimpleScriptContext" line="43"/>
                </scope>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="53">
                Executes the program stored in the &lt;code&gt;CompiledScript&lt;/code&gt; object.  The
                  default &lt;code&gt;ScriptContext&lt;/code&gt; of the associated &lt;code&gt;ScriptEngine&lt;/code&gt; is used.
                  The effect of calling this method is same as that of eval(getEngine().getContext()).                
                <return>
                    The return value from the script execution                    
                </return>
                <throws>
                    ScriptException if an error occurs.                    
                </throws>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="eval" type="Object" line="60"/>
            <method name="getEngine" type="ScriptEngine" line="63"/>
            <javadoc line="63">
                Returns the &lt;code&gt;ScriptEngine&lt;/code&gt; whose &lt;code&gt;compile&lt;/code&gt; method created this &lt;code&gt;CompiledScript&lt;/code&gt;.
                  The &lt;code&gt;CompiledScript&lt;/code&gt; will execute in this engine.                
                <return>
                    The <code>ScriptEngine</code> that created this <code>CompiledScript</code>                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
        </class>
    </source>