<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="sun.awt.im">
        <import package="java.awt.Component"/>
        <import package="java.awt.Rectangle"/>
        <import package="java.awt.im.spi.InputMethod"/>
        <class name="InputMethodAdapter" line="5">
            <implements interface="InputMethod"/>
            <javadoc line="5">
                An input method adapter interfaces with the native input methods
                  on a host platform. In general, it looks to the input method
                  framework like a Java input method (that may support a few more
                  locales than a typical Java input method). However, since it
                  often has to work in a slightly hostile environment that&apos;s not
                  designed for easy integration into the Java input method
                  framework, it gets some special treatment that&apos;s not available
                  to Java input methods.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  Licensees are free to modify this class as necessary to implement
                  their host input method adapters.                
                <author>
                    JavaSoft International                    
                </author>
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="clientComponent" type="Component" line="20"/>
            <method name="setClientComponent" type="void" line="21">
                <params>
                    <param name="client" type="Component"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <method name="getClientComponent" type="Component" line="24"/>
            <method name="haveActiveClient" type="boolean" line="27"/>
            <javadoc line="30">
                Informs the input method adapter about the component that has the AWT
                  focus if it&apos;s using the input context owning this adapter instance.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="setAWTFocussedComponent" type="void" line="34">
                <params>
                    <param name="component" type="Component"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="36">
                Returns whether host input methods can support below-the-spot input.
                  Returns false by default.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="supportsBelowTheSpot" type="boolean" line="40"/>
            <javadoc line="43">
                Informs the input method adapter not to listen to the native events.
                  This method is called when a Java input method is active.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="stopListening" type="void" line="47"/>
            <javadoc line="49">
                Notifies client Window location or status changes                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="notifyClientWindowChange" type="void" line="52">
                <params>
                    <param name="location" type="Rectangle"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="54">
                Starts reconvertion. An implementing host adapter has to override
                  this method if it can support reconvert().                
                <exception>
                    UnsupportedOperationException when the adapter does not override
                      the method.                    
                </exception>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="reconvert" type="void" line="60"/>
            <method name="disableInputMethod" type="void" line="63"/>
            <javadoc line="63">
                Disable the native input method. This method is provided for explicitly
                  turning off the native IM. The native IM is not turned off
                  when the native input method is deactivated. This method is
                  always called on AWT EDT. See details in bug 6226489.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getNativeInputMethodInfo" type="String" line="70"/>
            <javadoc line="70">
                Returns a string with information about the native input method, or
                  null.                
            </javadoc>
        </class>
    </source>