<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="java.security">
        <import package="java.security.spec.AlgorithmParameterSpec"/>
        <class name="KeyPairGeneratorSpi" line="30">
            <javadoc line="30">
                &lt;p&gt; This class defines the &lt;i&gt;Service Provider Interface&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;b&gt;SPI&lt;/b&gt;)
                  for the &lt;code&gt;KeyPairGenerator&lt;/code&gt; class, which is used to generate
                  pairs of public and private keys.
                  &lt;p&gt; All the abstract methods in this class must be implemented by each
                  cryptographic service provider who wishes to supply the implementation
                  of a key pair generator for a particular algorithm.
                  &lt;p&gt; In case the client does not explicitly initialize the KeyPairGenerator
                  (via a call to an &lt;code&gt;initialize&lt;/code&gt; method), each provider must
                  supply (and document) a default initialization.
                  For example, the &lt;i&gt;Sun&lt;/i&gt; provider uses a default modulus size (keysize)
                  of 1024 bits.                
                <author>
                    Benjamin Renaud                    
                </author>
                <see>
                    KeyPairGenerator                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    java.security.spec.AlgorithmParameterSpec                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="initialize" type="void" line="54"/>
            <javadoc line="54">
                Initializes the key pair generator for a certain keysize, using
                  the default parameter set.                
                <param>
                    keysize the keysize. This is an
                      algorithm-specific metric, such as modulus length, specified in
                      number of bits.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    random the source of randomness for this generator.                    
                </param>
                <exception>
                    InvalidParameterException if the <code>keysize</code> is not
                      supported by this KeyPairGeneratorSpi object.                    
                </exception>
            </javadoc>
            <javadoc line="69">
                Initializes the key pair generator using the specified parameter
                  set and user-provided source of randomness.
                  &lt;p&gt;This concrete method has been added to this previously-defined
                  abstract class. (For backwards compatibility, it cannot be abstract.)
                  It may be overridden by a provider to initialize the key pair
                  generator. Such an override
                  is expected to throw an InvalidAlgorithmParameterException if
                  a parameter is inappropriate for this key pair generator.
                  If this method is not overridden, it always throws an
                  UnsupportedOperationException.                
                <param>
                    params the parameter set used to generate the keys.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    random the source of randomness for this generator.                    
                </param>
                <exception>
                    InvalidAlgorithmParameterException if the given parameters
                      are inappropriate for this key pair generator.                    
                </exception>
                <since>
                    1.2                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="initialize" type="void" line="93">
                <params>
                    <param name="params" type="AlgorithmParameterSpec"/>
                    <param name="random" type="SecureRandom"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <method name="generateKeyPair" type="KeyPair" line="97"/>
            <javadoc line="97">
                Generates a key pair. Unless an initialization method is called
                  using a KeyPairGenerator interface, algorithm-specific defaults
                  will be used. This will generate a new key pair every time it
                  is called.                
                <return>
                    the newly generated <tt>KeyPair</tt>                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
        </class>
    </source>