<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="java.awt.font">
        <import package="java.awt.Font"/>
        <interface name="MultipleMaster">
            <javadoc line="3">
                The &lt;code&gt;MultipleMaster&lt;/code&gt; interface represents Type 1
                  Multiple Master fonts.
                  A particular {@link Font} object can implement this interface.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getNumDesignAxes" type="int" line="9"/>
            <javadoc line="9">
                Returns the number of multiple master design controls.
                  Design axes include things like width, weight and optical scaling.                
                <return>
                    the number of multiple master design controls                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getDesignAxisRanges" type="float[]" line="15"/>
            <javadoc line="15">
                Returns an array of design limits interleaved in the form [from-&gt;to]
                  for each axis.  For example,
                  design limits for weight could be from 0.1 to 1.0. The values are
                  returned in the same order returned by
                  &lt;code&gt;getDesignAxisNames&lt;/code&gt;.                
                <return>
                    an array of design limits for each axis.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getDesignAxisDefaults" type="float[]" line="24"/>
            <javadoc line="24">
                Returns an array of default design values for each axis.  For example,
                  the default value for weight could be 1.6. The values are returned
                  in the same order returned by &lt;code&gt;getDesignAxisNames&lt;/code&gt;.                
                <return>
                    an array of default design values for each axis.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getDesignAxisNames" type="String[]" line="31"/>
            <javadoc line="31">
                Returns the name for each design axis. This also determines the order in
                  which the values for each axis are returned.                
                <return>
                    an array containing the names of each design axis.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="deriveMMFont" type="Font" line="37"/>
            <javadoc line="37">
                Creates a new instance of a multiple master font based on the design
                  axis values contained in the specified array. The size of the array
                  must correspond to the value returned from
                  &lt;code&gt;getNumDesignAxes&lt;/code&gt; and the values of the array elements
                  must fall within limits specified by
                  &lt;code&gt;getDesignAxesLimits&lt;/code&gt;. In case of an error,
                  &lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt; is returned.                
                <param>
                    axes an array containing axis values                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    a {@link Font} object that is an instance of
                      &lt;code&gt;MultipleMaster&lt;/code&gt; and is based on the design axis values
                      provided by &lt;code&gt;axes&lt;/code&gt;.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="deriveMMFont" type="Font" line="51"/>
            <javadoc line="51">
                Creates a new instance of a multiple master font based on detailed metric
                  information. In case of an error, &lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt; is returned.                
                <param>
                    glyphWidths an array of floats representing the desired width
                      of each glyph in font space                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    avgStemWidth the average stem width for the overall font in
                      font space                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    typicalCapHeight the height of a typical upper case char                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    typicalXHeight the height of a typical lower case char                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    italicAngle the angle at which the italics lean, in degrees
                      counterclockwise from vertical                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    a &lt;code&gt;Font&lt;/code&gt; object that is an instance of
                      &lt;code&gt;MultipleMaster&lt;/code&gt; and is based on the specified metric
                      information.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
        </interface>
    </source>