<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="java.net">
        <import package="java.security.cert.Certificate"/>
        <import package="javax.net.ssl.SSLPeerUnverifiedException"/>
        <import package="java.security.Principal"/>
        <import package="java.util.List"/>
        <class name="SecureCacheResponse" line="6">
            <extends class="CacheResponse"/>
            <javadoc line="6">
                Represents a cache response originally retrieved through secure
                  means, such as TLS.                
                <since>
                    1.5                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getCipherSuite" type="String" line="12"/>
            <javadoc line="12">
                Returns the cipher suite in use on the original connection that
                  retrieved the network resource.                
                <return>
                    a string representing the cipher suite                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getLocalCertificateChain" type="List<Certificate>" line="18"/>
            <javadoc line="18">
                Returns the certificate chain that were sent to the server during
                  handshaking of the original connection that retrieved the
                  network resource.  Note: This method is useful only
                  when using certificate-based cipher suites.                
                <return>
                    an immutable List of Certificate representing the
                      certificate chain that was sent to the server. If no
                      certificate chain was sent, null will be returned.                    
                </return>
                <see>
                    #getLocalPrincipal()                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getServerCertificateChain" type="List<Certificate>" line="29"/>
            <javadoc line="29">
                Returns the server&apos;s certificate chain, which was established as
                  part of defining the session in the original connection that
                  retrieved the network resource, from cache.  Note: This method
                  can be used only when using certificate-based cipher suites;
                  using it with non-certificate-based cipher suites, such as
                  Kerberos, will throw an SSLPeerUnverifiedException.                
                <return>
                    an immutable List of Certificate representing the server's
                      certificate chain.                    
                </return>
                <throws>
                    SSLPeerUnverifiedException if the peer is not verified.                    
                </throws>
                <see>
                    #getPeerPrincipal()                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getPeerPrincipal" type="Principal" line="42"/>
            <javadoc line="42">
                Returns the server&apos;s principal which was established as part of
                  defining the session during the original connection that
                  retrieved the network resource.                
                <return>
                    the server's principal. Returns an X500Principal of the
                      end-entity certiticate for X509-based cipher suites, and
                      KerberosPrincipal for Kerberos cipher suites.                    
                </return>
                <throws>
                    SSLPeerUnverifiedException if the peer was not verified.                    
                </throws>
                <see>
                    #getServerCertificateChain()                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    #getLocalPrincipal()                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getLocalPrincipal" type="Principal" line="54"/>
            <javadoc line="54">
                Returns the principal that was sent to the server during
                  handshaking in the original connection that retrieved the
                  network resource.                
                <return>
                    the principal sent to the server. Returns an X500Principal
                      of the end-entity certificate for X509-based cipher suites, and
                      KerberosPrincipal for Kerberos cipher suites. If no principal was
                      sent, then null is returned.                    
                </return>
                <see>
                    #getLocalCertificateChain()                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    #getPeerPrincipal()                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
        </class>
    </source>