<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="java.beans">
        <class name="PropertyChangeEvent" line="28">
            <extends class="java.util.EventObject"/>
            <javadoc line="28">
                A &quot;PropertyChange&quot; event gets delivered whenever a bean changes a &quot;bound&quot;
                  or &quot;constrained&quot; property.  A PropertyChangeEvent object is sent as an
                  argument to the PropertyChangeListener and VetoableChangeListener methods.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  Normally PropertyChangeEvents are accompanied by the name and the old
                  and new value of the changed property.  If the new value is a primitive
                  type (such as int or boolean) it must be wrapped as the
                  corresponding java.lang. Object type (such as Integer or Boolean).
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  Null values may be provided for the old and the new values if their
                  true values are not known.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  An event source may send a null object as the name to indicate that an
                  arbitrary set of if its properties have changed.  In this case the
                  old and new values should also be null.                
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="serialVersionUID" type="long" line="47"/>
            <javadoc line="49">
                Constructs a new &lt;code&gt;PropertyChangeEvent&lt;/code&gt;.                
                <param>
                    source  The bean that fired the event.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    propertyName  The programmatic name of the property
                      that was changed.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    oldValue  The old value of the property.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    newValue  The new value of the property.                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="PropertyChangeEvent" type="constructor" line="59">
                <params>
                    <param name="source" type="Object"/>
                    <param name="propertyName" type="String"/>
                    <param name="oldValue" type="Object"/>
                    <param name="newValue" type="Object"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="66">
                Gets the programmatic name of the property that was changed.                
                <return>
                    The programmatic name of the property that was changed.
                      May be null if multiple properties have changed.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getPropertyName" type="String" line="72"/>
            <javadoc line="76">
                Gets the new value for the property, expressed as an Object.                
                <return>
                    The new value for the property, expressed as an Object.
                      May be null if multiple properties have changed.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getNewValue" type="Object" line="82"/>
            <javadoc line="86">
                Gets the old value for the property, expressed as an Object.                
                <return>
                    The old value for the property, expressed as an Object.
                      May be null if multiple properties have changed.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getOldValue" type="Object" line="92"/>
            <javadoc line="96">
                Sets the propagationId object for the event.                
                <param>
                    propagationId  The propagationId object for the event.                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="setPropagationId" type="void" line="101">
                <params>
                    <param name="propagationId" type="Object"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="105">
                The &quot;propagationId&quot; field is reserved for future use.  In Beans 1.0
                  the sole requirement is that if a listener catches a PropertyChangeEvent
                  and then fires a PropertyChangeEvent of its own, then it should
                  make sure that it propagates the propagationId field from its
                  incoming event to its outgoing event.                
                <return>
                    the propagationId object associated with a bound/constrained
                      property update.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getPropagationId" type="Object" line="115"/>
            <declaration name="propertyName" type="String" line="119"/>
            <javadoc line="119">
                name of the property that changed.  May be null, if not known.                
                <serial>
                                        
                </serial>
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="newValue" type="Object" line="125"/>
            <javadoc line="125">
                New value for property.  May be null if not known.                
                <serial>
                                        
                </serial>
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="oldValue" type="Object" line="131"/>
            <javadoc line="131">
                Previous value for property.  May be null if not known.                
                <serial>
                                        
                </serial>
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="propagationId" type="Object" line="137"/>
            <javadoc line="137">
                Propagation ID.  May be null.                
                <serial>
                                        
                </serial>
                <see>
                    #getPropagationId                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <javadoc line="144">
                Returns a string representation of the object.                
                <return>
                    a string representation of the object                    
                </return>
                <since>
                    1.7                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="toString" type="String" line="151">
                <declaration name="sb" type="StringBuilder" line="152"/>
            </method>
            <method name="appendTo" type="void" line="162">
                <params>
                    <param name="sb" type="StringBuilder"/>
                </params>
            </method>
        </class>
    </source>