<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="java.beans">
        <class name="SimpleBeanInfo" line="28">
            <implements interface="BeanInfo"/>
            <javadoc line="28">
                This is a support class to make it easier for people to provide
                  BeanInfo classes.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  It defaults to providing &quot;noop&quot; information, and can be selectively
                  overriden to provide more explicit information on chosen topics.
                  When the introspector sees the &quot;noop&quot; values, it will apply low
                  level introspection and design patterns to automatically analyze
                  the target bean.                
            </javadoc>
            <javadoc line="41">
                Deny knowledge about the class and customizer of the bean.
                  You can override this if you wish to provide explicit info.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getBeanDescriptor" type="BeanDescriptor" line="45"/>
            <javadoc line="49">
                Deny knowledge of properties. You can override this
                  if you wish to provide explicit property info.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getPropertyDescriptors" type="PropertyDescriptor[]" line="53"/>
            <javadoc line="57">
                Deny knowledge of a default property. You can override this
                  if you wish to define a default property for the bean.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getDefaultPropertyIndex" type="int" line="61"/>
            <javadoc line="65">
                Deny knowledge of event sets. You can override this
                  if you wish to provide explicit event set info.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getEventSetDescriptors" type="EventSetDescriptor[]" line="69"/>
            <javadoc line="73">
                Deny knowledge of a default event. You can override this
                  if you wish to define a default event for the bean.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getDefaultEventIndex" type="int" line="77"/>
            <javadoc line="81">
                Deny knowledge of methods. You can override this
                  if you wish to provide explicit method info.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getMethodDescriptors" type="MethodDescriptor[]" line="85"/>
            <javadoc line="89">
                Claim there are no other relevant BeanInfo objects.  You
                  may override this if you want to (for example) return a
                  BeanInfo for a base class.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getAdditionalBeanInfo" type="BeanInfo[]" line="94"/>
            <javadoc line="98">
                Claim there are no icons available.  You can override
                  this if you want to provide icons for your bean.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getIcon" type="java.awt.Image" line="102">
                <params>
                    <param name="iconKind" type="int"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="106">
                This is a utility method to help in loading icon images.
                  It takes the name of a resource file associated with the
                  current object&apos;s class file and loads an image object
                  from that file.  Typically images will be GIFs.
                  &lt;p&gt;                
                <param>
                    resourceName  A pathname relative to the directory
                      holding the class file of the current class.  For example,
                      "wombat.gif".                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    an image object.  May be null if the load failed.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="loadImage" type="java.awt.Image" line="117">
                <params>
                    <param name="resourceName" type="String"/>
                </params>
                <scope line="118">
                    <declaration name="c" type="Class" line="119"/>
                    <anonymous_class line="122">
                        <method name="run" type="Object" line="123">
                            <declaration name="url" type="java.net.URL" line="124"/>
                            <scope line="125"/>
                            <scope line="127">
                                <scope line="128"/>
                                <scope line="130"/>
                            </scope>
                        </method>
                    </anonymous_class>
                    <declaration name="ip" type="java.awt.image.ImageProducer" line="120"/>
                    <declaration name="tk" type="java.awt.Toolkit" line="139"/>
                </scope>
                <scope line="141"/>
            </method>
        </class>
    </source>