<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="sun.util.resources">
        <import package="java.util.Map"/>
        <import package="java.util.LinkedHashMap"/>
        <class name="TimeZoneNamesBundle" line="4">
            <extends class="OpenListResourceBundle"/>
            <javadoc line="4">
                Subclass of &lt;code&gt;ResourceBundle&lt;/code&gt; with special
                  functionality for time zone names. The additional functionality:
                  &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Preserves the order of entries in the &lt;code&gt;getContents&lt;/code&gt;
                  array for the enumeration returned by &lt;code&gt;getKeys&lt;/code&gt;.
                  &lt;li&gt;Inserts the time zone ID (the key of the bundle entries) into
                  the string arrays returned by &lt;code&gt;handleGetObject&lt;/code&gt;.
                  &lt;ul&gt;
                  All &lt;code&gt;TimeZoneNames&lt;/code&gt; resource bundles must extend this
                  class and implement the &lt;code&gt;getContents&lt;/code&gt; method.                
            </javadoc>
            <javadoc line="17">
                Maps time zone IDs to locale-specific names.
                  The value returned is an array of five strings:
                  &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;The time zone ID (same as the key, not localized).
                  &lt;li&gt;The long name of the time zone in standard time (localized).
                  &lt;li&gt;The short name of the time zone in standard time (localized).
                  &lt;li&gt;The long name of the time zone in daylight savings time (localized).
                  &lt;li&gt;The short name of the time zone in daylight savings time (localized).
                  &lt;/ul&gt;
                  The localized names come from the subclasses&apos;s
                  &lt;code&gt;getContents&lt;/code&gt; implementations, while the time zone
                  ID is inserted into the returned array by this method.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="handleGetObject" type="Object" line="31">
                <params>
                    <param name="key" type="String"/>
                </params>
                <declaration name="contents" type="String[]" line="32"/>
                <scope line="33"/>
                <declaration name="clen" type="int" line="36"/>
                <declaration name="tmpobj" type="String[]" line="37"/>
                <scope line="39"/>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="44">
                Use LinkedHashMap to preserve order of bundle entries.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="createMap" type="Map" line="47">
                <params>
                    <param name="size" type="int"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <method name="getContents" type="Object[][]" line="50"/>
            <javadoc line="50">
                Provides key/value mappings for a specific
                  resource bundle. Each entry of the array
                  returned must be an array with two elements:
                  &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;The key, which must be a string.
                  &lt;li&gt;The value, which must be an array of
                  four strings:
                  &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;The long name of the time zone in standard time.
                  &lt;li&gt;The short name of the time zone in standard time.
                  &lt;li&gt;The long name of the time zone in daylight savings time.
                  &lt;li&gt;The short name of the time zone in daylight savings time.
                  &lt;/ul&gt;
                  &lt;/ul&gt;                
            </javadoc>
        </class>
    </source>