<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="sun.text.resources">
        <import package="java.util.ListResourceBundle"/>
        <class name="BreakIteratorRules" line="49">
            <extends class="ListResourceBundle"/>
            <comment line="60">
                                
            </comment>
            <comment line="62">
                Since JDK 1.5.0, this file no longer goes to runtime and is used at J2SE
                 build phase in order to create [Character|Word|Line|Sentence]BreakIteratorData
                 files which are used on runtime instead.                
            </comment>
            <javadoc line="49">
                Default break-iterator rules.  These rules are more or less general for
                  all locales, although there are probably a few we&apos;re missing.  The
                  behavior currently mimics the behavior of BreakIterator in JDK 1.2.
                  There are known deficiencies in this behavior, including the fact that
                  the logic for handling CJK characters works for Japanese but not for
                  Chinese, and that we don&apos;t currently have an appropriate locale for
                  Thai.  The resources will eventually be updated to fix these problems.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getContents" type="Object[][]" line="68">
                <comment line="71">
                    rules describing how to break between logical characters                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="74">
                    ignore non-spacing marks and enclosing marks (since we never
                     put a break before ignore characters, this keeps combining
                     accents with the base characters they modify)                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="79">
                    other category definitions                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="86">
                    break after every character, except as follows:                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="89">
                    keep base and combining characters togethers                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="93">
                    keep CRLF sequences together                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="96">
                    keep surrogate pairs together                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="99">
                    keep Hangul syllables spelled out using conjoining jamo together                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="102">
                    various additions for Hindi support                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="118">
                    default rules for finding word boundaries                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="120">
                    ignore non-spacing marks, enclosing marks, and format characters,
                     all of which should not influence the algorithm
                    &quot;&lt;ignore&gt;=[:Mn::Me::Cf:];&quot;                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="127">
                    Hindi phrase separator, kanji, katakana, hiragana, CJK diacriticals,
                     other letters, and digits                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="139">
                    punctuation that can occur in the middle of a word: currently
                     dashes, apostrophes, quotation marks, and periods                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="143">
                    punctuation that can occur in the middle of a number: currently
                     apostrophes, qoutation marks, periods, commas, and the Arabic
                     decimal point                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="148">
                    punctuation that can occur at the beginning of a number: currently
                     the period, the number sign, and all currency symbols except the cents sign                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="152">
                    punctuation that can occur at the end of a number: currently
                     the percent, per-thousand, per-ten-thousand, and Arabic percent
                     signs, the cents sign, and the ampersand                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="157">
                    line separators: currently LF, FF, PS, and LS                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="160">
                    whitespace: all space separators and the tab character                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="164">
                    a word is a sequence of letters that may contain internal
                     punctuation, as long as it begins and ends with a letter and
                     never contains two punctuation marks in a row                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="169">
                    a number is a sequence of digits that may contain internal
                     punctuation, as long as it begins and ends with a digit and
                     never contains two punctuation marks in a row.                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="174">
                    break after every character, with the following exceptions
                     (this will cause punctuation marks that aren&apos;t considered
                     part of words or numbers to be treated as words unto themselves)                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="179">
                    keep together any sequence of contiguous words and numbers
                     (including just one of either), plus an optional trailing
                     number-suffix character                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="184">
                    keep together and sequence of contiguous words and numbers
                     that starts with a number-prefix character and a number,
                     and may end with a number-suffix character                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="189">
                    keep together runs of whitespace (optionally with a single trailing
                     line separator or CRLF sequence)                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="193">
                    keep together runs of Katakana and CJK diacritical marks                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="196">
                    keep together runs of Hiragana and CJK diacritical marks                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="199">
                    keep together runs of Kanji                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="202">
                    keep together anything else and an enclosing mark                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="207">
                    default rules for determining legal line-breaking positions                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="209">
                    characters that always cause a break: ETX, tab, LF, FF, LS, and PS                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="212">
                    ignore format characters and control characters EXCEPT for breaking chars                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="215">
                    enclosing marks                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="218">
                    Hindi phrase separators                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="221">
                    characters that always prevent a break: the non-breaking space
                     and similar characters                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="225">
                    whitespace: space separators and control characters, except for
                     CR and the other characters mentioned above                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="229">
                    dashes: dash punctuation and the discretionary hyphen, except for
                     non-breaking hyphens                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="233">
                    characters that stick to a word if they precede it: currency symbols
                     (except the cents sign) and starting punctuation                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="237">
                    characters that stick to a word if they follow it: ending punctuation,
                     other punctuation that usually occurs at the end of a sentence,
                     small Kana characters, some CJK diacritics, etc.                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="246">
                    Kanji: actually includes Kanji,Kana and Hangul syllables,
                     except for small Kana and CJK diacritics                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="250">
                    digits                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="253">
                    punctuation that can occur in the middle of a number: periods and commas                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="256">
                    everything not mentioned above                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="259">
                    a &quot;number&quot; is a run of prefix characters and dashes, followed by one or
                     more digits with isolated number-punctuation characters interspersed                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="263">
                    the basic core of a word can be either a &quot;number&quot; as defined above, a single
                     &quot;Kanji&quot; character, or a run of any number of not-explicitly-mentioned
                     characters (this includes Latin letters)                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="268">
                    a word may end with an optional suffix that be either a run of one or
                     more dashes or a run of word-suffix characters                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="272">
                    a word, thus, is an optional run of word-prefix characters, followed by
                     a word core and a word suffix (the syntax of &lt;word-core&gt; and &lt;word-suffix&gt;
                     actually allows either of them to match the empty string, putting a break
                     between things like &quot;)(&quot; or &quot;aaa(aaa&quot;                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="282">
                    finally, the rule that does the work: Keep together any run of words that
                     are joined by runs of one of more non-spacing mark.  Also keep a trailing
                     line-break character or CRLF combination with the word.  (line separators
                     &quot;win&quot; over nbsp&apos;s)                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="290">
                    default rules for finding sentence boundaries                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="292">
                    ignore non-spacing marks, enclosing marks, and format characters                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="295">
                    letters                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="298">
                    lowercase letters                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="301">
                    uppercase letters                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="304">
                    NOT lowercase letters                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="307">
                    whitespace (line separators are treated as whitespace)                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="310">
                    punctuation which may occur at the beginning of a sentence: &quot;starting
                     punctuation&quot; and quotation marks                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="314">
                    punctuation with may occur at the end of a sentence: &quot;ending punctuation&quot;
                     and quotation marks                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="318">
                    digits                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="321">
                    characters that unambiguously signal the end of a sentence                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="324">
                    periods, which MAY signal the end of a sentence                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="327">
                    characters that may occur at the beginning of a sentence: basically anything
                     not mentioned above (letters and digits are specifically excluded)                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="331">
                    Hindi phrase separator                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="334">
                    always break sentences after paragraph separators                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="337">
                    always break after a danda, if it&apos;s followed by whitespace                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="340">
                    if you see a period, skip over additional periods and ending punctuation
                     and if the next character is a paragraph separator, break after the
                     paragraph separator
                    + &quot;.*?&lt;period&gt;[&lt;period&gt;&lt;end&gt;]*&lt;space&gt;*\u2029;&quot;
                    + &quot;.*?[&lt;period&gt;&lt;end&gt;]*&lt;space&gt;*\u2029;&quot;                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="346">
                    if you see a period, skip over additional periods and ending punctuation,
                     followed by optional whitespace, followed by optional starting punctuation,
                     and if the next character is something that can start a sentence
                     (basically, a capital letter), then put the sentence break between the
                     whitespace and the opening punctuation                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="354">
                    if you see a sentence-terminating character, skip over any additional
                     terminators, periods, or ending punctuation, followed by any whitespace,
                     followed by a SINGLE optional paragraph separator, and put the break there                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="359">
                    The following rules are here to aid in backwards iteration.  The automatically
                     generated backwards state table will rewind to the beginning of the
                     paragraph all the time (or all the way to the beginning of the document
                     if the document doesn&apos;t use the Unicode PS character) because the only
                     unambiguous character pairs are those involving paragraph separators.
                     These specify a few more unambiguous breaking situations.                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="366">
                    if you see a sentence-starting character, followed by starting punctuation
                     (remember, we&apos;re iterating backwards), followed by an optional run of
                     whitespace, followed by an optional run of ending punctuation, followed
                     by a period, this is a safe place to turn around                    
                </comment>
                <comment line="372">
                    if you see a letter or a digit, followed by an optional run of
                     starting punctuation, followed by an optional run of whitespace,
                     followed by an optional run of ending punctuation, followed by
                     a sentence terminator, this is a safe place to turn around                    
                </comment>
            </method>
        </class>
    </source>