<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="javax.naming.directory">
        <import package="java.util.Hashtable"/>
        <import package="java.util.Enumeration"/>
        <import package="javax.naming.NamingException"/>
        <import package="javax.naming.NamingEnumeration"/>
        <interface name="Attributes">
            <implements interface="Cloneable"/>
            <implements interface="java.io.Serializable"/>
            <comment line="180">
                Use serialVersionUID from JNDI 1.1.1 for interoperability                
            </comment>
            <comment line="183">
                static final long serialVersionUID = -7247874645443605347L;                
            </comment>
            <javadoc line="35">
                This interface represents a collection of attributes.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  In a directory, named objects can have associated with them
                  attributes.  The Attributes interface represents a collection of attributes.
                  For example, you can request from the directory the attributes
                  associated with an object.  Those attributes are returned in
                  an object that implements the Attributes interface.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  Attributes in an object that implements the  Attributes interface are
                  unordered. The object can have zero or more attributes.
                  Attributes is either case-sensitive or case-insensitive (case-ignore).
                  This property is determined at the time the Attributes object is
                  created. (see BasicAttributes constructor for example).
                  In a case-insensitive Attributes, the case of its attribute identifiers
                  is ignored when searching for an attribute, or adding attributes.
                  In a case-sensitive Attributes, the case is significant.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  Note that updates to Attributes (such as adding or removing an attribute)
                  do not affect the corresponding representation in the directory.
                  Updates to the directory can only be effected
                  using operations in the DirContext interface.                
                <author>
                    Rosanna Lee                    
                </author>
                <author>
                    Scott Seligman                    
                </author>
                <see>
                    DirContext#getAttributes                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    DirContext#modifyAttributes                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    DirContext#bind                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    DirContext#rebind                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    DirContext#createSubcontext                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    DirContext#search                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    BasicAttributes                    
                </see>
                <since>
                    1.3                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="isCaseIgnored" type="boolean" line="72"/>
            <javadoc line="72">
                Determines whether the attribute set ignores the case of
                  attribute identifiers when retrieving or adding attributes.                
                <return>
                    true if case is ignored; false otherwise.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="size" type="int" line="79"/>
            <javadoc line="79">
                Retrieves the number of attributes in the attribute set.                
                <return>
                    The nonnegative number of attributes in this attribute set.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="get" type="Attribute" line="86"/>
            <javadoc line="86">
                Retrieves the attribute with the given attribute id from the
                  attribute set.                
                <param>
                    attrID The non-null id of the attribute to retrieve.
                      If this attribute set ignores the character
                      case of its attribute ids, the case of attrID
                      is ignored.                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    The attribute identified by attrID; null if not found.                    
                </return>
                <see>
                    #put                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    #remove                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getAll" type="NamingEnumeration<? extends Attribute>" line="100"/>
            <javadoc line="100">
                Retrieves an enumeration of the attributes in the attribute set.
                  The effects of updates to this attribute set on this enumeration
                  are undefined.                
                <return>
                    A non-null enumeration of the attributes in this attribute set.
                      Each element of the enumeration is of class <tt>Attribute</tt>.
                      If attribute set has zero attributes, an empty enumeration
                      is returned.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getIDs" type="NamingEnumeration<String>" line="112"/>
            <javadoc line="112">
                Retrieves an enumeration of the ids of the attributes in the
                  attribute set.
                  The effects of updates to this attribute set on this enumeration
                  are undefined.                
                <return>
                    A non-null enumeration of the attributes' ids in
                      this attribute set. Each element of the enumeration is
                      of class String.
                      If attribute set has zero attributes, an empty enumeration
                      is returned.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="put" type="Attribute" line="126"/>
            <javadoc line="126">
                Adds a new attribute to the attribute set.                
                <param>
                    attrID   non-null The id of the attribute to add.
                      If the attribute set ignores the character
                      case of its attribute ids, the case of attrID
                      is ignored.                    
                </param>
                <param>
                    val      The possibly null value of the attribute to add.
                      If null, the attribute does not have any values.                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    The Attribute with attrID that was previous in this attribute set;
                      null if no such attribute existed.                    
                </return>
                <see>
                    #remove                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="put" type="Attribute" line="141"/>
            <javadoc line="141">
                Adds a new attribute to the attribute set.                
                <param>
                    attr     The non-null attribute to add.
                      If the attribute set ignores the character
                      case of its attribute ids, the case of
                      attr's identifier is ignored.                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    The Attribute with the same ID as attr that was previous
                      in this attribute set;
                      null if no such attribute existed.                    
                </return>
                <see>
                    #remove                    
                </see>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="remove" type="Attribute" line="155"/>
            <javadoc line="155">
                Removes the attribute with the attribute id &apos;attrID&apos; from
                  the attribute set. If the attribute does not exist, ignore.                
                <param>
                    attrID   The non-null id of the attribute to remove.
                      If the attribute set ignores the character
                      case of its attribute ids, the case of
                      attrID is ignored.                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    The Attribute with the same ID as attrID that was previous
                      in the attribute set;
                      null if no such attribute existed.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="clone" type="Object" line="169"/>
            <javadoc line="169">
                Makes a copy of the attribute set.
                  The new set contains the same attributes as the original set:
                  the attributes are not themselves cloned.
                  Changes to the copy will not affect the original and vice versa.                
                <return>
                    A non-null copy of this attribute set.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
        </interface>
    </source>