<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="javax.print.attribute.standard">
        <import package="javax.print.attribute.Attribute"/>
        <import package="javax.print.attribute.EnumSyntax"/>
        <import package="javax.print.attribute.PrintServiceAttribute"/>
        <class name="ColorSupported" line="31">
            <extends class="EnumSyntax"/>
            <implements interface="PrintServiceAttribute"/>
            <javadoc line="31">
                Class ColorSupported is a printing attribute class, an enumeration, that
                  identifies whether the device is capable of any type of color printing at
                  all, including highlight color as well as full process color. All document
                  instructions having to do with color are embedded within the print data (none
                  are attributes attached to the job outside the print data).
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  Note: End users are able to determine the nature and details of the color
                  support by querying the {@link PrinterMoreInfoManufacturerPrinterMoreInfoManufacturer} attribute.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  Don&apos;t confuse the ColorSupported attribute with the {@link ChromaticityChromaticity} attribute. {@link Chromaticity Chromaticity} is an attribute
                  the client can specify for a job to tell the printer whether to print a
                  document in monochrome or color, possibly causing the printer to print a
                  color document in monochrome. ColorSupported is a printer description
                  attribute that tells whether the printer can print in color regardless of how
                  the client specifies to print any particular document.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  &lt;B&gt;IPP Compatibility:&lt;/B&gt; The IPP boolean value is &quot;true&quot; for SUPPORTED and
                  &quot;false&quot; for NOT_SUPPORTED. The category name returned by
                  &lt;CODE&gt;getName()&lt;/CODE&gt; is the IPP attribute name.  The enumeration&apos;s
                  integer value is the IPP enum value.  The &lt;code&gt;toString()&lt;/code&gt; method
                  returns the IPP string representation of the attribute value.
                  &lt;P&gt;                
                <author>
                    Alan Kaminsky                    
                </author>
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="serialVersionUID" type="long" line="62"/>
            <declaration name="NOT_SUPPORTED" type="ColorSupported" line="64"/>
            <javadoc line="64">
                The printer is not capable of any type of color printing.                
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="SUPPORTED" type="ColorSupported" line="69"/>
            <javadoc line="69">
                The printer is capable of some type of color printing, such as
                  highlight color or full process color.                
            </javadoc>
            <javadoc line="75">
                Construct a new color supported enumeration value with the given
                  integer value.                
                <param>
                    value  Integer value.                    
                </param>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="ColorSupported" type="constructor" line="81">
                <params>
                    <param name="value" type="int"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <declaration name="myStringTable" type="String[]" line="85"/>
            <declaration name="myEnumValueTable" type="ColorSupported[]" line="88"/>
            <javadoc line="91">
                Returns the string table for class ColorSupported.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getStringTable" type="String[]" line="94"/>
            <javadoc line="98">
                Returns the enumeration value table for class ColorSupported.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getEnumValueTable" type="EnumSyntax[]" line="101"/>
            <javadoc line="105">
                Get the printing attribute class which is to be used as the &quot;category&quot;
                  for this printing attribute value.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  For class ColorSupported, the category is class ColorSupported itself.                
                <return>
                    Printing attribute class (category), an instance of class{@link java.lang.Class java.lang.Class}.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getCategory" type="Class<? extends Attribute>" line="114"/>
            <javadoc line="118">
                Get the name of the category of which this attribute value is an
                  instance.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  For class ColorSupported, the category name is &lt;CODE&gt;&quot;color-supported&quot;&lt;/CODE&gt;.                
                <return>
                    Attribute category name.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getName" type="String" line="126"/>
        </class>
    </source>