<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="javax.print.attribute.standard">
        <import package="javax.print.attribute.Attribute"/>
        <import package="javax.print.attribute.IntegerSyntax"/>
        <import package="javax.print.attribute.PrintJobAttribute"/>
        <class name="JobKOctetsProcessed" line="5">
            <extends class="IntegerSyntax"/>
            <implements interface="PrintJobAttribute"/>
            <javadoc line="5">
                Class JobKOctetsProcessed is an integer valued printing attribute class that
                  specifies the total number of print data octets processed so far in K octets,
                  i.e., in units of 1024 octets. The value must be rounded up, so that a job
                  between 1 and 1024 octets inclusive must be indicated as being 1K octets,
                  1025 to 2048 inclusive must be 2K, etc. For a multidoc print job (a job with
                  multiple documents), the JobKOctetsProcessed value is computed by adding up
                  the individual documents&apos; number of octets processed so far, then rounding up
                  to the next K octets value.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  The JobKOctetsProcessed attribute describes the progress of the job. This
                  attribute is intended to be a counter. That is, the JobKOctetsProcessed value
                  for a job that has not started processing must be 0. When the job&apos;s {@link JobState JobState} is PROCESSING or PROCESSING_STOPPED, the
                  JobKOctetsProcessed value is intended to increase as the job is processed; it
                  indicates the amount of the job that has been processed at the time the Print
                  Job&apos;s attribute set is queried or at the time a print job event is reported.
                  When the job enters the COMPLETED, CANCELED, or ABORTED states, the
                  JobKOctetsProcessed value is the final value for the job.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  For implementations where multiple copies are produced by the interpreter
                  with only a single pass over the data, the final value of the
                  JobKOctetsProcessed attribute must be equal to the value of the {@link JobKOctets JobKOctets} attribute. For implementations where multiple copies
                  are produced by the interpreter by processing the data for each copy, the
                  final value must be a multiple of the value of the {@link JobKOctetsJobKOctets} attribute.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  &lt;B&gt;IPP Compatibility:&lt;/B&gt; The integer value gives the IPP integer value. The
                  category name returned by &lt;CODE&gt;getName()&lt;/CODE&gt; gives the IPP attribute
                  name.
                  &lt;P&gt;                
                <see>
                    JobKOctets                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    JobKOctetsSupported                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    JobImpressionsCompleted                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    JobMediaSheetsCompleted                    
                </see>
                <author>
                    Alan Kaminsky                    
                </author>
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="serialVersionUID" type="long" line="41"/>
            <javadoc line="42">
                Construct a new job K octets processed attribute with the given integer
                  value.                
                <param>
                    value  Integer value.                    
                </param>
                <exception>
                    IllegalArgumentException(Unchecked exception) Thrown if &lt;CODE&gt;value&lt;/CODE&gt; is less than 0.                    
                </exception>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="JobKOctetsProcessed" type="constructor" line="48">
                <params>
                    <param name="value" type="int"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="51">
                Returns whether this job K octets processed attribute is equivalent to
                  the passed in object. To be equivalent, all of the following conditions
                  must be true:
                  &lt;OL TYPE=1&gt;
                  &lt;LI&gt;
                  &lt;CODE&gt;object&lt;/CODE&gt; is not null.
                  &lt;LI&gt;
                  &lt;CODE&gt;object&lt;/CODE&gt; is an instance of class JobKOctetsProcessed.
                  &lt;LI&gt;
                  This job K octets processed attribute&apos;s value and
                  &lt;CODE&gt;object&lt;/CODE&gt;&apos;s value are equal.
                  &lt;/OL&gt;                
                <param>
                    object  Object to compare to.                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    True if &lt;CODE&gt;object&lt;/CODE&gt; is equivalent to this job K
                      octets processed attribute, false otherwise.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="equals" type="boolean" line="68">
                <params>
                    <param name="object" type="Object"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="71">
                Get the printing attribute class which is to be used as the &quot;category&quot;
                  for this printing attribute value.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  For class JobKOctetsProcessed, the category is class
                  JobKOctetsProcessed itself.                
                <return>
                    Printing attribute class (category), an instance of class{@link java.lang.Class java.lang.Class}.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getCategory" type="Class&lt;? extends Attribute&gt;" line="79"/>
            <javadoc line="82">
                Get the name of the category of which this attribute value is an
                  instance.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  For class JobKOctetsProcessed, the category name is
                  &lt;CODE&gt;&quot;job-k-octets-processed&quot;&lt;/CODE&gt;.                
                <return>
                    Attribute category name.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getName" type="String" line="90"/>
        </class>
    </source>