<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="javax.print.attribute.standard">
        <import package="javax.print.attribute.Attribute"/>
        <import package="javax.print.attribute.IntegerSyntax"/>
        <import package="javax.print.attribute.PrintRequestAttribute"/>
        <import package="javax.print.attribute.PrintJobAttribute"/>
        <class name="JobMediaSheets" line="6">
            <extends class="IntegerSyntax"/>
            <implements interface="PrintRequestAttribute"/>
            <implements interface="PrintJobAttribute"/>
            <javadoc line="6">
                Class JobMediaSheets is an integer valued printing attribute class that
                  specifies the total number of media sheets to be produced for this job.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  The JobMediaSheets attribute describes the size of the job. This attribute is
                  not intended to be a counter; it is intended to be useful routing and
                  scheduling information if known. The printer may try to compute the
                  JobMediaSheets attribute&apos;s value if it is not supplied in the Print Request.
                  Even if the client does supply a value for the JobMediaSheets attribute in
                  the Print Request, the printer may choose to change the value if the printer
                  is able to compute a value which is more accurate than the client supplied
                  value. The printer may be able to determine the correct value for the
                  JobMediaSheets attribute either right at job submission time or at any later
                  point in time.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  Unlike the {@link JobKOctets JobKOctets} and {@link JobImpressionsJobImpressions} attributes, the JobMediaSheets value must include the
                  multiplicative factors contributed by the number of copies specified by the{@link Copies Copies} attribute and a &quot;number of copies&quot; instruction embedded
                  in the document data, if any. This difference allows the system administrator
                  to control the lower and upper bounds of both (1) the size of the document(s)
                  with {@link JobKOctetsSupported JobKOctetsSupported} and {@link JobImpressionsSupported JobImpressionsSupported} and (2) the size of the job
                  with {@link JobMediaSheetsSupported JobMediaSheetsSupported}.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  &lt;B&gt;IPP Compatibility:&lt;/B&gt; The integer value gives the IPP integer value. The
                  category name returned by &lt;CODE&gt;getName()&lt;/CODE&gt; gives the IPP attribute
                  name.
                  &lt;P&gt;                
                <see>
                    JobMediaSheetsSupported                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    JobMediaSheetsCompleted                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    JobKOctets                    
                </see>
                <see>
                    JobImpressions                    
                </see>
                <author>
                    Alan Kaminsky                    
                </author>
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="serialVersionUID" type="long" line="39"/>
            <javadoc line="40">
                Construct a new job media sheets attribute with the given integer
                  value.                
                <param>
                    value  Integer value.                    
                </param>
                <exception>
                    IllegalArgumentException(Unchecked exception) Thrown if <CODE>value</CODE> is less than 0.                    
                </exception>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="JobMediaSheets" type="constructor" line="46">
                <params>
                    <param name="value" type="int"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="49">
                Returns whether this job media sheets attribute is equivalent to the
                  passed in object. To be equivalent, all of the following conditions must
                  be true:
                  &lt;OL TYPE=1&gt;
                  &lt;LI&gt;
                  &lt;CODE&gt;object&lt;/CODE&gt; is not null.
                  &lt;LI&gt;
                  &lt;CODE&gt;object&lt;/CODE&gt; is an instance of class JobMediaSheets.
                  &lt;LI&gt;
                  This job media sheets attribute&apos;s value and &lt;CODE&gt;object&lt;/CODE&gt;&apos;s
                  value are equal.
                  &lt;/OL&gt;                
                <param>
                    object  Object to compare to.                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    True if <CODE>object</CODE> is equivalent to this job media
                      sheets attribute, false otherwise.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="equals" type="boolean" line="66">
                <params>
                    <param name="object" type="Object"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="69">
                Get the printing attribute class which is to be used as the &quot;category&quot;
                  for this printing attribute value.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  For class JobMediaSheets and any vendor-defined subclasses, the category
                  is class JobMediaSheets itself.                
                <return>
                    Printing attribute class (category), an instance of class{@link java.lang.Class java.lang.Class}.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getCategory" type="Class<? extends Attribute>" line="77"/>
            <javadoc line="80">
                Get the name of the category of which this attribute value is an
                  instance.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  For class JobMediaSheets and any vendor-defined subclasses, the
                  category name is &lt;CODE&gt;&quot;job-media-sheets&quot;&lt;/CODE&gt;.                
                <return>
                    Attribute category name.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getName" type="String" line="88"/>
        </class>
    </source>