<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="javax.print.attribute.standard">
        <import package="javax.print.attribute.Attribute"/>
        <import package="javax.print.attribute.IntegerSyntax"/>
        <import package="javax.print.attribute.PrintRequestAttribute"/>
        <import package="javax.print.attribute.PrintJobAttribute"/>
        <class name="JobPriority" line="6">
            <extends class="IntegerSyntax"/>
            <implements interface="PrintRequestAttribute"/>
            <implements interface="PrintJobAttribute"/>
            <javadoc line="6">
                Class JobPriority is an integer valued printing attribute class that
                  specifies a print job&apos;s priority.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  If a JobPriority attribute is specified for a Print Job, it specifies a
                  priority for scheduling the job. A higher value specifies a higher priority.
                  The value 1 indicates the lowest possible priority. The value 100 indicates
                  the highest possible priority. Among those jobs that are ready to print, a
                  printer must print all jobs with a priority value of &lt;I&gt;n&lt;/I&gt; before printing
                  those with a priority value of &lt;I&gt;n&lt;/I&gt;-1 for all &lt;I&gt;n.&lt;/I&gt;
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  If the client does not specify a JobPriority attribute for a Print Job and
                  the printer does support the JobPriority attribute, the printer must use an
                  implementation-defined default JobPriority value.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  The client can always specify any job priority value from 1 to 100 for a job.
                  However, a Print Service instance may support fewer than 100 different
                  job priority levels. If this is the case, the Print Service instance
                  automatically maps the client-specified job priority value to one of the
                  supported job priority levels, dividing the 100 job priority values equally
                  among the available job priority levels.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  &lt;B&gt;IPP Compatibility:&lt;/B&gt; The integer value gives the IPP integer value. The
                  category name returned by &lt;CODE&gt;getName()&lt;/CODE&gt; gives the IPP attribute
                  name.
                  &lt;P&gt;                
                <author>
                    Alan Kaminsky                    
                </author>
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="serialVersionUID" type="long" line="35"/>
            <javadoc line="36">
                Construct a new job priority attribute with the given integer value.                
                <param>
                    value  Integer value.                    
                </param>
                <exception>
                    IllegalArgumentException(Unchecked exception) Thrown if <CODE>value</CODE> is less than 1
                      or greater than 100.                    
                </exception>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="JobPriority" type="constructor" line="42">
                <params>
                    <param name="value" type="int"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="45">
                Returns whether this job priority attribute is equivalent to the passed
                  in object. To be equivalent, all of the following conditions must be
                  true:
                  &lt;OL TYPE=1&gt;
                  &lt;LI&gt;
                  &lt;CODE&gt;object&lt;/CODE&gt; is not null.
                  &lt;LI&gt;
                  &lt;CODE&gt;object&lt;/CODE&gt; is an instance of class JobPriority.
                  &lt;LI&gt;
                  This job priority attribute&apos;s value and &lt;CODE&gt;object&lt;/CODE&gt;&apos;s value
                  are equal.
                  &lt;/OL&gt;                
                <param>
                    object  Object to compare to.                    
                </param>
                <return>
                    True if <CODE>object</CODE> is equivalent to this job
                      priority attribute, false otherwise.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="equals" type="boolean" line="62">
                <params>
                    <param name="object" type="Object"/>
                </params>
            </method>
            <javadoc line="65">
                Get the printing attribute class which is to be used as the &quot;category&quot;
                  for this printing attribute value.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  For class JobPriority, the category is class JobPriority itself.                
                <return>
                    Printing attribute class (category), an instance of class{@link java.lang.Class java.lang.Class}.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getCategory" type="Class<? extends Attribute>" line="72"/>
            <javadoc line="75">
                Get the name of the category of which this attribute value is an
                  instance.
                  &lt;P&gt;
                  For class JobPriority, the category name is &lt;CODE&gt;&quot;job-priority&quot;&lt;/CODE&gt;.                
                <return>
                    Attribute category name.                    
                </return>
            </javadoc>
            <method name="getName" type="String" line="82"/>
        </class>
    </source>