<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <source package="sun.io">
        <class name="Win32ErrorMode" line="28">
            <comment line="39">
                The system does not display the critical-error-handler message box. Instead,                
            </comment>
            <comment line="40">
                the system sends the error to the calling process.                
            </comment>
            <comment line="43">
                The system does not display the general-protection-fault message box. This flag should                
            </comment>
            <comment line="44">
                only be set by debugging applications that handle general protection (GP) faults themselves                
            </comment>
            <comment line="45">
                with an exception handler.                
            </comment>
            <comment line="48">
                The system automatically fixes memory alignment faults and makes them invisible                
            </comment>
            <comment line="49">
                to the application. It does this for the calling process and any descendant processes.                
            </comment>
            <comment line="52">
                The system does not display a message box when it fails to find a file. Instead,                
            </comment>
            <comment line="53">
                the error is returned to the calling process.                
            </comment>
            <comment line="80">
                Win32 SetErrorMode                
            </comment>
            <javadoc line="28">
                Used to set the Windows error mode at VM initialization time.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  The error mode decides whether the system will handle specific types of serious errors
                  or whether the process will handle them.                
                <since>
                    1.6                    
                </since>
            </javadoc>
            <declaration name="SEM_FAILCRITICALERRORS" type="long" line="40"/>
            <declaration name="SEM_NOGPFAULTERRORBOX" type="long" line="45"/>
            <declaration name="SEM_NOALIGNMENTFAULTEXCEPT" type="long" line="49"/>
            <declaration name="SEM_NOOPENFILEERRORBOX" type="long" line="53"/>
            <method name="Win32ErrorMode" type="constructor" line="55"/>
            <javadoc line="58">
                Invoke at VM initialization time to disable the critical error message box.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  The critial error message box is disabled unless the system property
                  &lt;tt&gt;sun.io.allowCriticalErrorMessageBox&lt;/tt&gt; is set to something other than
                  &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;. This includes the empty string.
                  &lt;p&gt;
                  This method does nothing if invoked after VM and class library initialization
                  has completed.                
            </javadoc>
            <method name="initialize" type="void" line="68">
                <scope line="69">
                    <declaration name="s" type="String" line="70"/>
                    <scope line="71">
                        <declaration name="mode" type="long" line="72"/>
                    </scope>
                </scope>
            </method>
            <method name="setErrorMode" type="long" line="80"/>
        </class>
    </source>